<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>recipe on</title><link>/tags/recipe/</link><description>Recent content in recipe on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</managingEditor><webMaster>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>5-SPICE FRIED RICE WITH SWEET POTATOES</title><link>/2022/04/02/SPICE-FRIED-RICE-WITH-SWEET-POTATOES/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/2022/04/02/SPICE-FRIED-RICE-WITH-SWEET-POTATOES/</guid><description>5-SPICE FRIED RICE WITH SWEET POTATOES yields 4 AS A SIDE OR YOUR LONELY ASS FOR A COUPLE ingredients 1 medium sweet potato (¾ to 1 LB) 2 tsp neutral-tasting oil (Grapeseed/peanut/sesame) 2 TBL water 1/2 small yellow onion 1 carrot carrot 1/4 tsp Chinese 5-spice powder 1 to 2 clove garlic to 2 clove garlic 1 1/2 TBL soy sauce or tamari 1 TBL rice vinegar 1 tsp chili paste or an Asian-style hot sauce like Sriracha 4 cup cooked short-grain brown rice that’s been chilled for a couple hours 1 cup bitter greens (watercress/mustard/arugula) 1/2 cup sliced green onions 1 cup frozen green peas, thawed instructions 0 chop onion, carrot, and greens no bigger than a quarter</description></item><item><title>Meatballs Marsala with Egg Noodles and Chives</title><link>/2022/04/02/Meatballs-Marsala/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/2022/04/02/Meatballs-Marsala/</guid><description>Meatballs Marsala with Egg Noodles and Chives ingredients TBL olive oil 2 TBL butter 1 small yellow onion 1 tsp salt 1/2 cup panko 1 large egg 1/4 cup milk 1/4 cup dry Marsala 3 TBL butter 3 TBL flour 1 3/4 cup chicken stock 1/4 cup heavy cream 12 oz egg noodles 1 TBL butter 4 tsp chives</description></item><item><title>ALMOND CAESAR SALAD WITH</title><link>/recipes/almond-caesar-salad-with2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/almond-caesar-salad-with2/</guid><description>ALMOND CAESAR SALAD WITH yields 4 SIDE SALADS ingredients 1/3 cup sliced or slivered almonds* 1/3 cup sliced or slivered almondst* 1/3 cup sliced or slivered almonds* 1/3 cup sliced or slivered almonds* 1/3 cup sliced or slivered almondso* 1/3 cup sliced or slivered almonds* 1/3 cup sliced or slivered almonds* 1/3 cup sliced or slivered almondss* 1/3 cup sliced or slivered almonds* 1/3 cup sliced or slivered almonds 1 TBL capers* 1 TBL capers* 1 TBL capers 1 handful Croutons instructions 0 chop up the lettuce 1 Put the almonds in a glass with the hot water and let those ers soak for about 15 minutes.</description></item><item><title>APPLE BAKED BEANS</title><link>/recipes/apple-baked-beans3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/apple-baked-beans3/</guid><description>APPLE BAKED BEANS yields 6 AS A SIDE ingredients 1 1/2 cup dried white beans* 1 1/2 cup dried white beans* 1 1/2 cup dried white beans
2 tsp olive oil
0.5 yellow onion
1 clove garlic* 1 clove garlicaprika
1 can (15 ounces) low- or no-salt tomato sauce can (15 ounces) low- or no-salt tomato sauce
1 TBL molasses* 1 TBL molassesd* 1 TBL molasses* 1 TBL molasses</description></item><item><title>APPLE-COCONUT BUNDT CAKE</title><link>/recipes/applecoconut-bundt-cake4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/applecoconut-bundt-cake4/</guid><description>APPLE-COCONUT BUNDT CAKE yields 1 CAKE, ENOUGH FOR 6 TO 8 PEOPLE ingredients 1 LB apples 2 TBL plus 3 cup whole wheat pastry or all-purpose flour 1 can (14 ounces) coconut milk, about 1.5 cup 2/3 cup unsweetened plain milk 2 TBL grapeseed or olive oil 1/2 cup sugar 1/4 cup packed brown sugar 2 tsp vanilla extract 1 TBL apple cider vinegar 2 tsp baking powder 1 tsp baking soda 1/2 tsp salt 2 tsp ground cinnamon 1/2 tsp ground ginger 1/8 tsp ground clove or cardamom 1 cup finely shredded unsweetened coconut Powdered sugar Whipped Cream Instructions peel and core apples and cut into small cubes no larger than a dime (about 3 cup) 1 Warm the oven to 325°F.</description></item><item><title>APPLE-ONION FOCACCIA</title><link>/recipes/appleonion-focaccia5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/appleonion-focaccia5/</guid><description>APPLE-ONION FOCACCIA yields 1 LOAF OF BREAD ingredients 2 tsp plus 2 TBL olive oil* 2 tsp plus 2 TBL olive oilw* 2 tsp plus 2 TBL olive oil* 2 tsp plus 2 TBL olive oil* 2 tsp plus 2 TBL olive oilice
1 TBL fresh thyme or rosemary Everyday Pizza Dough
1 TBL unsweetened nondairy milk of your choice BALSAMIC DIPPING SAUCE optional</description></item><item><title>ARTICHOKE DIP</title><link>/recipes/artichoke-dip6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/artichoke-dip6/</guid><description>ARTICHOKE DIP yields 2 cup, ENOUGH FOR 4 PEOPLE ingredients 3 clove garlic 1/2 cup unsweetened plain nondairy milk 1 1/2 tsp soy sauce 1/4 cup sliced almonds 1 can (14 ounces) water-packed artichoke hearts, drained and rinsed 2 TBL flour 2 TBL olive oil 1/2 cup vegetable broth 1 cup fresh spinach 1/4 cup nutritional yeast 1 TBL lemon juice Instructions 1 In a blender or food processor, combine the onion, garlic, milk, and soy sauce and pulse that until it looks like paste.</description></item><item><title>BAKED OKRA AND POTATO HASH</title><link>/recipes/baked-okra-and-potato-hash7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/baked-okra-and-potato-hash7/</guid><description>BAKED OKRA AND POTATO HASH yields 2 TO 3 AS A SIDE ingredients 1 LB yellow or red potatoes 1/2 yellow onion 1 LB okra 2 tsp olive oil 2 TBL cornmeal 1 dash ground pepper 1/4 tsp salt 1/2 tsp paprika BAKED OKRA AND POTATO HASH yields 2 TO 3 AS A SIDE ingredients 1 LB yellow or red potatoes 1/2 yellow onion 1 LB okra 2 tsp olive oil 2 TBL cornmeal 1 dash ground pepper 1/4 tsp salt 1/2 tsp paprika ng sheet and put that mother er in the oven.</description></item><item><title>BAKED RICE AND LEEK CAKES</title><link>/recipes/baked-rice-and-leek-cakes8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/baked-rice-and-leek-cakes8/</guid><description>BAKED RICE AND LEEK CAKES yields 24 CAKES, ENOUGH FOR 6 TO 8 PEOPLE ingredients 12 ounces extra-firm silken tofu 1 TBL rice vinegar 1 TBL toasted sesame oil 1 TBL soy sauce or tamari 1 tsp neutral oil, such as grapeseed 2 cup diced leeks ½ cup minced chives or green onions 1 TBL minced fresh ginger 2 clove garlic 2 ½ cup cooked short-grain white or brown rice 1 ¼ cup panko bread crumbs Spray oil Sweet Sesame Teriyaki-Style Sauce instructions 1 Crank up your oven to 425°F.</description></item><item><title>BAKED SPANISH RICE</title><link>/recipes/baked-spanish-rice9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/baked-spanish-rice9/</guid><description>BAKED SPANISH RICE yields 4 TO 6 AS A SIDE OR 8 AS BURRITO FILLING ingredients 2 tomatoes tomatoes
3 clove garlic
1 jalapeño jalapeño
1 TBL tomato paste* 1 TBL tomato pastet* 1 TBL tomato paste* 1 TBL tomato paste* 1 TBL tomato pastee* 1 TBL tomato paste* 1 TBL tomato paste* 1 TBL tomato pasten* 1 TBL tomato paste
1 cup green peas</description></item><item><title>BAKED SPICY PLANTAIN CHIPS</title><link>/recipes/baked-spicy-plantain-chips10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/baked-spicy-plantain-chips10/</guid><description>BAKED SPICY PLANTAIN CHIPS yields 4 TO 6, ABOUT 30 CHIPS, DEPENDING ON THE ingredients 1 green plantain green plantain
1 TBL olive or grapeseed oil* 1 TBL olive or grapeseed oilc* 1 TBL olive or grapeseed oil* 1 TBL olive or grapeseed oil* 1 TBL olive or grapeseed oile pepper
1/4 tsp salt
instructions 1 Crank your oven to 400°F. Grab a baking sheet and coat it lightly with cooking spray.</description></item><item><title>BAKED SPRING ROLLS</title><link>/recipes/baked-spring-rolls11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/baked-spring-rolls11/</guid><description>BAKED SPRING ROLLS yields 12 ROLLS, DEPENDING ON THE SIZE OF THE WRAPPERS YOU GRAB ingredients 2 tsp neutral oil, such as grapeseed 1 cup sliced shiitake or button mushrooms 1 carrot, cut into thin matchsticks 1 large rib celery, cut into thin matchsticks 1 head of napa or green cabbage, cut into bite-size strips (about 4.5 cup) 1/4 cup minced green onions 1 cup cooked glass noodles 1 1/2 TBL soy sauce or tamari 1 TBL rice vinegar 1/4 tsp black pepper 12 large spring roll wrappers Spray oil DIPPING SAUCE (optional) 1 TBL soy sauce or tamari 1 TBL rice vinegar 1 TBL water 1 tsp Asian-style hot sauce 1 tsp toasted sesame oil 1 tsp agave syrup 1 clove garlic Instructions 1 Crank your oven to 400°F.</description></item><item><title>BAKED ZITI WITH SPINACH</title><link>/recipes/baked-ziti-with-spinach12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/baked-ziti-with-spinach12/</guid><description>BAKED ZITI WITH SPINACH yields 4 TO 6 PEOPLE ingredients 1 can (14 ounces) water-packed artichoke hearts, drained and rinsed 12 ounces firm silken tofu, drained 1/4 cup sliced almonds 3 TBL nutritional yeast 2 TBL lemon juice 3 clove garlic, 2 whole and 1 minced 1/4 tsp salt 2 tsp olive oil 0.5 yellow onion 4 cup spinach Squeeze of lemon juice 1 pinch salt 1/4 cup fresh basil 1 LB pasta, cooked 3 cup Quick Blender Marinara or Blender Red Sauce 3 TBL bread crumbs 1 TBL nutritional yeast 1/4 tsp garlic powder 1 TBL olive oil Instructions 0 chop onion</description></item><item><title>BAKED ZUCCHINI CHIPS</title><link>/recipes/baked-zucchini-chips13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/baked-zucchini-chips13/</guid><description>BAKED ZUCCHINI CHIPS yields 4 TO 6, ABOUT 30 CHIPS, DEPENDING ON THE ingredients 1 medium zucchini, about 4 inches long and 1.5 inches wide 1 TBL flour 1/4 tsp smoked paprika 1/4 tsp garlic powder 1 pinch salt Instructions 1 Heat your oven to 350°F. Lightly coat a baking sheet with cooking spray.
2 Cut the zucchini into coins a little thicker than a quarter. If you cut them too thin they will</description></item><item><title>BANANA AND COCONUT POPS</title><link>/recipes/banana-and-coconut-pops14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/banana-and-coconut-pops14/</guid><description>BANANA AND COCONUT POPS yields 5 cup FILLING, ENOUGH FOR 10 POPS ingredients 6 ripe bananas 1 cup canned coconut milk 1 1/2 cup nondairy yogurt 3 TBL maple syrup or agave syrup 2 TBL orange juice 1 TBL ground cinnamon 2 tsp vanilla extract Instructions 1 Throw everything into a blender and give it a goddamn whirl until there are no chunks of banana left in there and everything looks smooth.</description></item><item><title>BANANA CREAM PIE</title><link>/recipes/banana-cream-pie15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/banana-cream-pie15/</guid><description>BANANA CREAM PIE yields 1 PIE, ENOUGH FOR 8 PEOPLE ingredients 1 1/2 cup flour 1 TBL sugar 1/2 tsp salt 1/4 tsp baking powder 1/4 cup butter 2 TBL olive or grapeseed oil 2-3 TBL almond milk 1/4 cup cornstarch or arrowroot powder 1/4 cup sugar 1 pinch salt 1 can (13.5 ounces) coconut milk 1 cup plain almond or other nondairy milk 1 1/2 tsp vanilla extract 3 large ripe bananas Whipped Cream Instructions 1 Make the crust: Heat your oven to 350°F.</description></item><item><title>BARLEY-STUFFED PEPPERS</title><link>/recipes/barleystuffed-peppers16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/barleystuffed-peppers16/</guid><description>BARLEY-STUFFED PEPPERS yields 4 STUFFED PEPPERS ingredients 2 TBL olive oil 0.5 onion 2 ribs celery 1 carrot 3 to 4 clove garlic 2 tsp dried thyme 1 1/2 tsp dried oregano 1 cup pearled barley 1 tomato 2 TBL sherry vinegar or red wine vinegar 2 cup vegetable broth 1/2 tsp salt 1/4 tsp ground pepper 4 bell peppers, whatever color you find is cool 1 1/2 cup cooked kidney or white beans 1/4 cup fresh parsley Instructions 0 chop onion, celery, carrots, tomato</description></item><item><title>BASIC BALSAMIC AND WHITE WINE VINAIGRETTE</title><link>/recipes/basic-balsamic-and-white-wine-vinaigrette17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/basic-balsamic-and-white-wine-vinaigrette17/</guid><description>BASIC BALSAMIC AND WHITE WINE VINAIGRETTE ingredients 1 clove garlic 1 tsp Dijon mustard 2 TBL balsamic vinegar 2 TBL white wine vinegar 1/4 cup olive oil Instructions Pour all this together in a jar and shake the out of it. Taste and add more of whateverthe you think it needs. Refrigerate until go-time.</description></item><item><title>BASIC MAPLE GRANOLA WITH ADD-IN IDEAS</title><link>/recipes/basic-maple-granola-with-addin-ideas18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/basic-maple-granola-with-addin-ideas18/</guid><description>BASIC MAPLE GRANOLA WITH ADD-IN IDEAS yields 5 cup ingredients 3 cup rolled oats 1/2 cup sunflower seeds 1/2 cup almonds 1/4 cup uncooked millet 1/2 cup maple syrup 1/3 cup olive oil 1/2 tsp vanilla extract 1/2 tsp ground cinnamon 1/2 tsp salt 1/2 cup dried cranberries (optional) Instructions 1 Heat your oven to 300°F. Line a rimmed baking sheet with some parchment paper.
2 Mix together the oats, seeds, nuts, and millet in a large bowl.</description></item><item><title>BASIC THUG KITCHEN VINAIGRETTE</title><link>/recipes/basic-thug-kitchen-vinaigrette19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/basic-thug-kitchen-vinaigrette19/</guid><description>BASIC THUG KITCHEN VINAIGRETTE ingredients 2 TBL diced shallot or sweet onion* 2 TBL diced shallot or sweet onionn* 2 TBL diced shallot or sweet onion* 2 TBL diced shallot or sweet onion* 2 TBL diced shallot or sweet onioninegar
1/4 cup olive oil
instructions Pour all this together in a jar and shake the out of it. Taste and add more of whateverthe you think it needs.</description></item><item><title>BBQ BEAN BURRITOS WITH GRILLED PEACH SALSA</title><link>/recipes/bbq-bean-burritos-with-grilled-peach-salsa20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/bbq-bean-burritos-with-grilled-peach-salsa20/</guid><description>BBQ BEAN BURRITOS WITH GRILLED PEACH SALSA yields 6 BIG-ASS BURRITOS ingredients 3 TBL tomato paste 3 to 4 clove garlic 4 chipotle peppers in adobo sauce plus 1 TBL of the sauce 1/4 cup vegetable broth or water 2 TBL orange juice 2 TBL light brown sugar 1 TBL molasses 1 tsp soy sauce or tamari 3 cup cooked pinto beans 6 flour tortillas Baked Spanish Rice Shredded lettuce Grilled Peach Salsa Sliced avocado Instructions 1 First, make the BBQ beans: Throw the onion, tomato paste, garlic, chipotle peppers and</description></item><item><title>BBQ BEAN SLIDERS WITH CELERY SEED SLAW</title><link>/recipes/bbq-bean-sliders-with-celery-seed-slaw21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/bbq-bean-sliders-with-celery-seed-slaw21/</guid><description>BBQ BEAN SLIDERS WITH CELERY SEED SLAW yields 12 SLIDERS OR 6 REGULAR-SIZE BURGERS ingredients Burgers 3 cup cooked kidney beans 1 ½ cup grated zucchini (about 2 medium) ½ medium onion 2 clove garlic 1 TBL olive oil 2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 2 tsp liquid smoke 1 tsp seasoning blend ½ cup bread crumbs Spray oil Slaw 0.5 LB cabbage, sliced into thin strips (about 4 cup) 1 carrot, shredded (about .</description></item><item><title>BIG-ASS SALAD BOWL</title><link>/recipes/bigass-salad-bowl22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/bigass-salad-bowl22/</guid><description>BIG-ASS SALAD BOWL yields 1 BIG-ASS SALAD, ENOUGH FOR 6 TO 8 PEOPLE ingredients 10 cup mixed greens 1 cucumber, cut into thin rounds 2 ribs celery 2 medium tomatoes 2 carrots, shaved into thin strips with your veggie peeler 1 avocado 1/2 medium red onion, sliced into thin strips 2 small beets, roasted and cut into cubes or matchsticks 1/4 cup fresh herbs 1 1/2 cup cooked beans, such as garbanzo, kidney, or black beans Whatever dressing you are feeling Salt and Black pepper Instructions 0 chop celery and tomatoes and herbs; slice avacado</description></item><item><title>BISCUITS AND GRAVY</title><link>/recipes/biscuits-and-gravy23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/biscuits-and-gravy23/</guid><description>BISCUITS AND GRAVY yields 4 TO 6 ingredients 1 1/2 cup green or brown lentils 5 cup water Salt 1/2 small onion 1 tsp olive oil 1 tsp dried thyme 2 clove garlic 1/8 tsp ground pepper 1 TBL flour 1 cup vegetable broth 1 tsp soy sauce or tamari 1 tsp paprika 1/2 tsp sherry or red wine vinegar Whole Wheat Biscuits Instructions 0 mince garlic and dice onion</description></item><item><title>BLACK BEAN AND CORN SALAD</title><link>/recipes/black-bean-and-corn-salad24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/black-bean-and-corn-salad24/</guid><description>BLACK BEAN AND CORN SALAD yields 4 PEOPLE, OR A BADASS SIDE AT A GRILL-OUT ingredients 2 medium red or orange bell peppers 0.5 red onion 2 tsp olive oil 3 cup cooked black beans 1 jalapeño, seeded and minced optional 1/3 cup cilantro instructions 0 chop cilantro; Chop the bell peppers and onion up until they are about the size of beans.
1 Grab a medium skillet or wok and heat up the oil over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>BLACK BEAN TORTAS WITH COCONUT CHIPOTLE MAYO</title><link>/recipes/black-bean-tortas-with-coconut-chipotle-mayo25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/black-bean-tortas-with-coconut-chipotle-mayo25/</guid><description>BLACK BEAN TORTAS WITH COCONUT CHIPOTLE MAYO yields 4 TORTAS ingredients 1 cup canned coconut milk 1/3 cup of your favorite chipotle hot sauce 1/4 cup olive oil 1 TBL ground chia seeds 1 tsp lemon juice 1/2 tsp garlic powder 1 pinch salt 1 tsp oil 1 yellow onion 3 clove garlic 1 TBL chili powder 3/4 tsp ground cumin 3 cup cooked black beans 1 1/2 cup vegetable broth 1 tsp lime juice Salt to taste 4 crusty rolls, split and toasted Lettuce Sliced tomatoes Sliced red onion Sliced avocado Instructions 0 chop onion</description></item><item><title>BLACKBERRY-LEMON BUCKLE</title><link>/recipes/blackberrylemon-buckle26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/blackberrylemon-buckle26/</guid><description>BLACKBERRY-LEMON BUCKLE yields 1 CAKE, ENOUGH FOR 6 TO 8 PEOPLE ingredients 1 tsp ground cinnamon ½ tsp ground ginger 3 TBL olive or grapeseed oil 1 cup unsweetened plain nondairy milk 1 tsp lemon juice or apple cider vinegar 1 TBL loosely packed grated lemon zest 1/3 cup granulated sugar ¼ cup olive or grapeseed oil 1 tsp vanilla extract 1 ¼ cup whole wheat pastry or all-purpose flour ½ cup oat flour 2 ½ tsp baking powder ½ tsp salt 2 cup fresh or frozen blackberries instructions 1 Heat up the oven to 375°F.</description></item><item><title>BLACKBERRY-MINT SPIKED LEMONADE</title><link>/recipes/blackberrymint-spiked-lemonade27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/blackberrymint-spiked-lemonade27/</guid><description>BLACKBERRY-MINT SPIKED LEMONADE yields 6 cup ingredients 2 lemons into chunks lemons into chunks 15 large mint leaves 0.25 to .5 cup sugar 2 cup fresh or frozen blackberries 3/4 cup bourbon instructions 0 chop lemons
1 Throw the lemon chunks, mint, .25 cup sugar, blackberries, and water into the blender and let it go until everything is chopped up, about 1 minute. Use a fine-mesh strainer/sieve or some cheesecloth to strain out all the chunky bits when you pour it into a pitcher.</description></item><item><title>BLENDED EARL GREY LATTES</title><link>/recipes/blended-earl-grey-lattes28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/blended-earl-grey-lattes28/</guid><description>BLENDED EARL GREY LATTES yields 2 TALL DRINKS ingredients 2 cup vanilla almond milk 1/2 cup water 4 bags Earl Grey tea 1-2 tsp maple syrup or agave syrup 2 cup ice cubes 0.5 banana, cut into chunks and frozen Instructions 1 In a small saucepan, heat the almond milk and water over medium heat until it starts to
bubble around the edges. Turn off the heat and add the tea bags.</description></item><item><title>BLENDER RED SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/blender-red-sauce29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/blender-red-sauce29/</guid><description>BLENDER RED SAUCE yields 5 cup ingredients 2 red bell peppers 1 can (15 ounces) no-salt-added tomato sauce 2 clove garlic Instructions 0 roast bell peppers
1 Throw all that in a blender and run it until the sauce looks saucy. You know what the that means. This will keep in the fridge for 2 weeks, no problem.
Modifications Optional, but way worth it. Learn how to roast those ers up.</description></item><item><title>BLUEBERRY SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/blueberry-sauce30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/blueberry-sauce30/</guid><description>BLUEBERRY SAUCE yields 1 CUP ingredients 2 TBL sugar* 2 TBL sugari* 2 TBL sugar* 2 TBL sugar* 2 TBL sugarextract
2 large pieces lemon zest
instructions 1 Throw everything together in a small saucepan over medium-low heat. It may not look like enough liquid, but once the berries start breaking down you’ll see what the is up. Stir it around, smashing some berries with your spoon as you go.</description></item><item><title>BLUEBERRY WALNUT LAVENDER SCONES</title><link>/recipes/blueberry-walnut-lavender-scones31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/blueberry-walnut-lavender-scones31/</guid><description>BLUEBERRY WALNUT LAVENDER SCONES yields 12 SCONES. BEST SERVED THE DAY THEY ARE MADE. ingredients 1 cup flour 1 TBL baking powder 1 tsp vanilla extract 1/2 cup walnuts instructions 1 Crank your oven to 425°F. Line a baking sheet with parchment paper or foil. 2 In a large bowl, mix together the flour, baking powder, sugars, and salt. Cut the oil into the flour using your hands until it all looks kind of grainy and there are no large chunks left.</description></item><item><title>BOOZY WATERMELON AND PAPAYA SALAD</title><link>/recipes/boozy-watermelon-and-papaya-salad32/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/boozy-watermelon-and-papaya-salad32/</guid><description>BOOZY WATERMELON AND PAPAYA SALAD yields 4 TO 6 PEOPLE ingredients 2 TBL lime juice* 2 TBL lime juice* 2 TBL lime juice* 2 TBL lime juice* 2 TBL lime juicel* 2 TBL lime juice* 2 TBL lime juice 1 small watermelon* 1 small watermelonl papaya 0.5 red onion, thinly sliced
optional *
1 jalapeño, seeded and diced jalapeño, seeded and diced
1/4 cup cilantro* 1/4 cup cilantro</description></item><item><title>BRAISED RADISH BITES</title><link>/recipes/braised-radish-bites33/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/braised-radish-bites33/</guid><description>BRAISED RADISH BITES yields 4 PEOPLE ingredients 1 bunch of radishes (about 10 globes) bunch of radishes (about 10 globes)
2 tsp olive oil* 2 tsp olive oil * 2 tsp olive oil* 2 tsp olive oil* 2 tsp olive oil vinegar
1 pinch salt Parsley, for garnish optional
instructions 1 Radishes are dirty little ers, so make sure to rinse the hell outta them before you get cooking.</description></item><item><title>BRAISED WINTER CABBAGE AND POTATOES</title><link>/recipes/braised-winter-cabbage-and-potatoes34/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/braised-winter-cabbage-and-potatoes34/</guid><description>BRAISED WINTER CABBAGE AND POTATOES yields 4 TO 6 AS A SIDE ingredients 1 small head of green cabbage (about 1 LB) 0.5 yellow onion 3 carrots 1 cup vegetable broth 2 TBL olive oil 0.5 LB small white or golden potatoes 3 clove garlic 1 TBL fresh rosemary Salt pepper 1 TBL lemon juice Instructions 1 Heat your oven to 350°F.
2 Chop the cabbage in half and slice into wedges no thicker than 2 inches.</description></item><item><title>BREAKFAST GREENS</title><link>/recipes/breakfast-greens35/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/breakfast-greens35/</guid><description>BREAKFAST GREENS yields 2 TO 4 AS A SIDE ingredients 1 1/2 tsp maple syrup or agave syrup 1 tsp tomato paste 1 tsp liquid smoke 2 tsp soy sauce 2 tsp olive or grapeseed oil 8 ounces tempeh 2 clove garlic 1 1/2 tsp seasoning blend 1 bunch kale 2 TBL lemon juice Instructions 0 mince garlic; cut kale into 2-inch strips (about 7 cup)
1 In a small glass, mix together the broth, maple syrup, tomato paste, liquid smoke, and 1</description></item><item><title>BREAKFAST TEMPEH AND POTATO TACO BAR</title><link>/recipes/breakfast-tempeh-and-potato-taco-bar36/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/breakfast-tempeh-and-potato-taco-bar36/</guid><description>BREAKFAST TEMPEH AND POTATO TACO BAR ingredients small yellow or red potatoes 8 ounces tempeh 1 large red bell pepper 0.5 yellow onion 1/4 cup vegetable broth or water 2 tsp olive oil 1 TBL lime juice 2 clove garlic 1 TBL chili powder 1 tsp paprika 1/2 tsp ground cumin 1/2 tsp salt 8 to 10 tortillas Toppings: salsa, hot sauce, shredded lettuce, avocado slices or guacamole, cilantro, lime wedges, jalapeño slices Instructions 1 Warm up your oven to 400°F.</description></item><item><title>BROWN RICE BOWL WITH EDAMAME AND TAMARI SCALLION SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/brown-rice-bowl-with-edamame-and-tamari-scallion-sauce37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/brown-rice-bowl-with-edamame-and-tamari-scallion-sauce37/</guid><description>BROWN RICE BOWL WITH EDAMAME AND TAMARI SCALLION SAUCE yields 4 TO 6 ingredients 1 cup sliced green onions 1/4 cup rice vinegar 2 TBL orange juice 4 tsp toasted sesame oil 1 tsp tamari or soy sauce 1 Pot Brown Rice 4 cup shelled edamame 1/3 cup sliced almonds (optional) Instructions 1 Make the sauce: Throw everything into a food processor or blender and let it run until the</description></item><item><title>BRUSCHETTA</title><link>/recipes/bruschetta38/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/bruschetta38/</guid><description>BRUSCHETTA yields 5 cup TOPING, ABOUT 16 BITES, ENOUGH FOR 2 TO 4 PEOPLE ingredients 5 fist-size tomatoes 1/4 cup fresh basil (10 to 12 leaves) 2 tsp lemon juice 2 tsp balsamic vinegar 2 tsp olive oil 1/8 tsp salt 1 clove garlic Crusty bread slices, toasted Instructions 0 chop tomatoes
1 Mix all that together (except the bread, dumbass) in a medium bowl and let it chill in the fridge for 30 minutes so all the flavors can hang out and get to know each other.</description></item><item><title>BUFFALO LETTUCE BITES</title><link>/recipes/buffalo-lettuce-bites39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/buffalo-lettuce-bites39/</guid><description>BUFFALO LETTUCE BITES ingredients 3 cup cooked chickpeas butter, or green leaf lettuce, something that can hold a scoop Buffalo Sauce, for serving Instructions 0 chop celery
1 Dump the chickpeas in a food processor until they’re nice and chopped up. Dump the mashed chickpeas into a big bowl. Throw in the celery, carrot, red onion, garlic, lemon juice, red wine vinegar, olive oil, salt, and pepper and stir.</description></item><item><title>BUFFALO PIZZA</title><link>/recipes/buffalo-pizza40/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/buffalo-pizza40/</guid><description>BUFFALO PIZZA yields 2 INDIVIDUAL PIZZAS ingredients 1 TBL all-purpose 1 TBL apple cider vinegar 3/4 cup hot sauce 2 tsp olive oil 8 ounces tempeh, crumbled 1/4 cup yellow onion 1 clove garlic 3 TBL all-purpose flour 2 TBL olive oil 1 1/2 cup unsweetened nondairy milk 1 clove garlic 1/4 tsp salt 2 TBL nutritional yeast 1/4 tsp dried basil 1/4 tsp dried dill 1/4 tsp celery seed 1 TBL lemon juice Olive oil, for brushing the crust 1 cup finely chopped celery 0.</description></item><item><title>BUFFALO SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/buffalo-sauce41/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/buffalo-sauce41/</guid><description>BUFFALO SAUCE yields 5 cup ingredients 2 TBL olive oil* 2 TBL olive oilo* 2 TBL olive oil* 2 TBL olive oil* 2 TBL olive oile
1 TBL apple cider vinegar or lemon juice
instructions 1 Grab a small saucepot and warm up the oil over a medium heat. Add the flour and stir that up until it starts smelling nutty, about 2 minutes. Whisk in the broth.</description></item><item><title>BUTTERNUT SQUASH QUESO-ISH DIP</title><link>/recipes/butternut-squash-quesoish-dip42/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/butternut-squash-quesoish-dip42/</guid><description>BUTTERNUT SQUASH QUESO-ISH DIP yields 5 cup, ENOUGH FOR 6 HUNGRY MOTHER ERS ingredients 1 1/2 cup butternut squash puree 1/2 cup diced yellow onion 3 TBL all-purpose or whole wheat flour 1 1/2 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp chili powder 1 tsp smoked paprika 3 TBL olive oil 1/2 cup vegetable broth or water 1 cup diced tomatoes with their juices 1/4 cup nutritional yeast 2 clove garlic 1 or 2 jalapeños, minced 1 TBL lime juice 1/2 tsp salt Instructions 1 Throw the butternut squash puree and onion in a blender and run until that er looks smooth.</description></item><item><title>CALIFORNIA CITRUS AND ALMOND SALAD</title><link>/recipes/california-citrus-and-almond-salad43/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/california-citrus-and-almond-salad43/</guid><description>CALIFORNIA CITRUS AND ALMOND SALAD yields 1 BIG-ASS SALAD, MORE THAN ENOUGH FOR 4 TO 6 PEOPLE ingredients 3 TBL rice vinegar* 3 TBL rice vinegars* 3 TBL rice vinegar* 3 TBL rice vinegar
1 tsp agave syrup or your favorite liquid sweetener* 1 tsp agave syrup or your favorite liquid sweetenere, tough ribs removed, cut into strips (about 4 cup) bunch of kale, tough ribs removed, cut into strips (about 4 cup)</description></item><item><title>CARROT CAKE COOKIES</title><link>/recipes/carrot-cake-cookies44/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/carrot-cake-cookies44/</guid><description>CARROT CAKE COOKIES yields 20 COOKIES ingredients 1 1/2 cup flour (whole wheat pastry or white) 1/2 cup packed light brown sugar 1 tsp baking powder 1/2 tsp salt 1/2 tsp ground cinnamon 1/2 tsp ground ginger 1 cup shredded carrots 1/2 cup plain almond or other nondairy milk 1/4 cup olive or grapeseed oil 1/2 cup walnuts 1/2 cup raisins or chopped candied ginger Instructions 1 Heat your oven to 375°F.</description></item><item><title>CARROT DOGS</title><link>/recipes/carrot-dogs45/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/carrot-dogs45/</guid><description>CARROT DOGS yields 8 DOGS, ENOUGH FOR 4 TO 8 PEOPLE ingredients 1 cup vegetable broth 1/4 cup apple cider vinegar 2 TBL rice vinegar 2 TBL soy sauce 1/2 tsp liquid smoke 1 TBL paprika 2 tsp mustard powder or ground mustard seed 1/2 tsp garlic powder 1/2 tsp ground coriander 1/4 tsp finely ground black pepper 2 TBL olive oil 8 medium carrots 8 hotdog buns, whatever kind of you like Topping ideas: smoky onions (from Cobb Salad), your favorite chili, dill relish, mustard, ketchup Instructions 0 peel carrots and cut the length of the buns</description></item><item><title>CAULIFLOWER CREAM PASTA WITH</title><link>/recipes/cauliflower-cream-pasta-with46/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/cauliflower-cream-pasta-with46/</guid><description>CAULIFLOWER CREAM PASTA WITH yields 4 ingredients 1 LB pasta (fettuccine, linguine, spaghetti, whatever)* 1 LB pasta (fettuccine, linguine, spaghetti, whatever) Salt and pepper
1 LB cauliflower* 1 LB cauliflowertened plain nondairy milk
2 or 3 clove garlic or 3 clove garlic
1 TBL lemon juice* 1 TBL lemon juicel* 1 TBL lemon juice* 1 TBL lemon juice
1/3 cup minced fresh parsley</description></item><item><title>CHEATER SAUERKRAUT</title><link>/recipes/cheater-sauerkraut47/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/cheater-sauerkraut47/</guid><description>CHEATER SAUERKRAUT yields 4 cup ingredients 6 cup shredded cabbage, red or green 4 bay leaves bay leaves 3 clove garlic 1/2 tsp salt 1/4 cup fresh dill optional instructions 1 Warm up a large skillet with a lid over medium heat. Add the cabbage and enough water for it to be about halfway submerged. Fold in the bay leaves, garlic, vinegar, sugar, and salt and bring to a simmer.</description></item><item><title>CHERRY TOMATO GALETTES</title><link>/recipes/cherry-tomato-galettes48/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/cherry-tomato-galettes48/</guid><description>CHERRY TOMATO GALETTES yields 2 GALETTES, ENOUGH FOR 4 PEOPLE ingredients 2 tsp olive oil 1 yellow onion, sliced 3 cup halved cherry tomatoes 1/4 tsp salt 2 clove garlic 1 TBL balsamic vinegar 2 TBL fresh basil, plus more for garnish Olive oil, for brushing the crusts Instructions 1 Make the pie crust through step 2. Let it chill out in the fridge while you make the filling.</description></item><item><title>CHEX-ISH MIX</title><link>/recipes/chexish-mix49/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/chexish-mix49/</guid><description>CHEX-ISH MIX yields 10 cup ingredients 8 cup square, waffle-cut cereal, such as Chex 1 tsp garlic powder* 1 tsp garlic powderpowder 1/8 tsp cayenne pepper optional 1/8 tsp black pepper* 1/8 tsp black pepper 1/4 cup olive oil instructions 1 Warm the oven to 250°F. Pull out 2 rimmed baking sheets and set that aside. 2 Grab a big-ass bowl and dump in the cereal, pretzels, and nuts.</description></item><item><title>CHICKPEAS AND DUMPLINGS</title><link>/recipes/chickpeas-and-dumplings50/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/chickpeas-and-dumplings50/</guid><description>CHICKPEAS AND DUMPLINGS yields 6 HUNGRY MOTHER ERS ingredients 2 tsp olive oil 1 bunch of chives 2 cup all-purpose flour 2 tsp baking powder 3/4 tsp garlic powder 1/4 tsp salt 1 TBL olive oil 1 cup almond milk 5 leaves kale 2 sweet onions 2 carrots 3 ribs of celery 1 small crown of broccoli 3 to 4 clove garlic 1/4 cup olive oil Salt CHICKPEAS AND DUMPLINGS yields 6 HUNGRY MOTHER ERS ingredients 2 tsp olive oil 1 bunch of chives 2 cup all-purpose flour 2 tsp baking powder 3/4 tsp garlic powder 1/4 tsp salt 1 TBL olive oil 1 cup almond milk 5 leaves kale 2 sweet onions 2 carrots 3 ribs of celery 1 small crown of broccoli 3 to 4 clove garlic 1/4 cup olive oil Salt ed up sizes because that’s how is, but don’t stress.</description></item><item><title>CHOCOLATE CHIP AND ALMOND BUTTER COOKIES</title><link>/recipes/chocolate-chip-and-almond-butter-cookies51/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/chocolate-chip-and-almond-butter-cookies51/</guid><description>CHOCOLATE CHIP AND ALMOND BUTTER COOKIES yields 24 COOKIES ingredients 1 ½ cup flour ½ tsp baking powder ½ tsp baking soda ½ tsp salt 2/3 cup chilled almond butter 1/3 cup brown sugar 1/3 cup white sugar 2 TBL ground flaxseed ¾ cup almond milk 1 ½ tsp vanilla extract 0.5 to 2⁄3 cup semisweet chocolate chips Instructions 1 In a medium bowl, sift together the flour, baking powder, baking soda, and salt.</description></item><item><title>CHOCOLATE FUDGE POPS</title><link>/recipes/chocolate-fudge-pops52/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/chocolate-fudge-pops52/</guid><description>CHOCOLATE FUDGE POPS yields 33 cup FILLING, about 12 POPS ingredients 1 cup vanilla almond or your favorite nondairy milk* 1 cup vanilla almond or your favorite nondairy milksweet chocolate chips
12 ounces firm silken tofu ounces firm silken tofu* 12 ounces firm silken tofu ounces firm silken tofuicks popsicle sticks
Popsicle molds or 12 small-ass paper cup
instructions 1 Warm up the milk on the stovetop or in the microwave so that it is warm but not super hot.</description></item><item><title>CHOCOLATE-ALMOND HAYSTACKS</title><link>/recipes/chocolatealmond-haystacks53/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/chocolatealmond-haystacks53/</guid><description>CHOCOLATE-ALMOND HAYSTACKS yields 18 ingredients 1 1/2 cup semisweet chocolate chips* 1 1/2 cup semisweet chocolate chips* 1 1/2 cup semisweet chocolate chips* 1 1/2 cup semisweet chocolate chips 1/2 tsp sea salt instructions 1 Line a rimmed baking sheet with some parchment or wax paper. 2 Melt the chocolate chips in a double boiler, homemade fake-out, or the microwave. Add the butter to the chocolate chips and stir until everything is melted and mixed together.</description></item><item><title>CHOCOLATE-COCONUT PIE</title><link>/recipes/chocolatecoconut-pie54/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/chocolatecoconut-pie54/</guid><description>CHOCOLATE-COCONUT PIE yields 1 PIE ingredients 14 oz coconut milk* 14 oz coconut milke* 14 oz coconut milk* 14 oz coconut milk 1 pinch salt Whipped Cream instructions 0 chill coconut milk 1 Make the pie crust through step 3. Let it chill out in the fridge while you make the filling. Also, start cranking your oven up to 400°F. 2 Follow the instructions to roll out and blind bake the crust.</description></item><item><title>CHOCOLATE-DIPPED TANGERINES</title><link>/recipes/chocolatedipped-tangerines55/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/chocolatedipped-tangerines55/</guid><description>CHOCOLATE-DIPPED TANGERINES yields 30 SLICES, DEPENDING ON YOUR CITRUS ingredients 5 or 6 tangerines, clementines, or tiny oranges of any kind 1/2 cup semisweet chocolate chips 1 tsp butter 1/2 tsp sea salt Instructions 1 Peel the fruit and break them up into segments. Try to get all that white pith off because
that will taste bitter. Lay the segments on a baking sheet lined with wax paper in some</description></item><item><title>CILANTRO PESTO</title><link>/recipes/cilantro-pesto56/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/cilantro-pesto56/</guid><description>CILANTRO PESTO yields 1 CUP ingredients 2 cup cilantro (about 1 big bunch) 1/2 cup slivered or sliced almonds 2 to 3 clove garlic 1/2 tsp grated lemon zest 1 TBL lemon juice 1/4 tsp salt 1/4 cup olive oil 1/4 cup vegetable broth or water Instructions 0 chop garlic
1 Throw the cilantro, almonds, garlic, lemon zest, lemon juice, salt, oil, and broth in a food processor and blend until sorta smooth and, you know, pesto looking.</description></item><item><title>COBB SALAD</title><link>/recipes/cobb-salad58/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/cobb-salad58/</guid><description>COBB SALAD yields 4 TO 6 PEOPLE ingredients 1 tsp yellow mustard 1 tsp maple syrup or agave syrup 1 or 2 clove garlic 1/3 cup red wine vinegar 1 TBL rice vinegar 1/3 cup olive oil 1 tsp olive oil 1/2 large yellow onion 1 tsp soy sauce or tamari 1 tsp water 1 tsp liquid smoke MISO-GLAZED CHICKPEAS 2 TBL vegetable broth or water 2 tsp red miso paste 1/2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 2 tsp olive oil 1 1/2 cup cooked chickpeas 2 tsp nutritional yeast 1/4 tsp garlic powder 1 romaine heart 1 head of red leaf lettuce Salt and black pepper 1 avocado 2 fist-size tomatoes 1/2 cup chives Instructions 0 chop romaine hear, red leaf lettuce, avacado, and tomatoes; slice onion</description></item><item><title>COCONUT CORNMEAL CAKE</title><link>/recipes/coconut-cornmeal-cake59/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/coconut-cornmeal-cake59/</guid><description>COCONUT CORNMEAL CAKE yields 1 Cake ingredients 1 1/4 cup cornmeal* 1 1/4 cup cornmeal* 1 1/4 cup cornmeal* 1 1/4 cup cornmeal* 1 1/4 cup cornmealo* 1 1/4 cup cornmeal* 1 1/4 cup cornmeal* 1 1/4 cup cornmealed coconut milk
1 tsp vanilla extract* 1 tsp vanilla extract lemon zest
instructions 1 First, heat your oven to 375°F. Grab an 8-inch cake pan, grease it, and dust it with flour to make sure your cake doesn’t stick.</description></item><item><title>COCONUT PANCAKES WITH MANGO COULIS</title><link>/recipes/coconut-pancakes-with-mango-coulis60/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/coconut-pancakes-with-mango-coulis60/</guid><description>COCONUT PANCAKES WITH MANGO COULIS ingredients 2 mangoes, cut into cubes 2-4 TBL sugar 1 1/2 tsp lemon juice 2 1/4 cup sweetened vanilla nondairy milk or coconut milk 1/2 tsp lemon juice or apple cider vinegar 1 TBL ground flaxseed 2 cup flour, all-purpose flour, or a mix 1/2 cup shredded coconut, toasted 3 TBL brown sugar 2 tsp baking soda 1/8 tsp salt Spray oil fresh-cut fruit Instructions 1 To make the coulis: Throw everything in a food processor or blender and let that er run until it’s nice and smooth.</description></item><item><title>COLD CITRUS NOODLES WITH</title><link>/recipes/cold-citrus-noodles-with62/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/cold-citrus-noodles-with62/</guid><description>COLD CITRUS NOODLES WITH ingredients 2 small carrots 2 small cucumbers 2/3 cup thinly sliced green onions 1 1/2 TBL toasted sesame seeds Instructions 0 cut carrots and cucumber into matchsticks
1 Mix all the ingredients for the citrus sesame sauce together in a small glass.
2 Cook the noodles according to the package directions, because all that is different.
When they are done, drain and rinse them with cold water so that they stop cooking and don’t</description></item><item><title>CORN AND BASIL CHOWDER</title><link>/recipes/corn-and-basil-chowder64/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/corn-and-basil-chowder64/</guid><description>CORN AND BASIL CHOWDER yields 4 TO 6 AS A SIDE ingredients 6 large ears corn, shucked &amp;lt; title: &amp;ldquo;CORN AND BASIL CHOWDER&amp;rdquo; tags:
recipe CORN AND BASIL CHOWDER yields 4 TO 6 AS A SIDE ingredients 6 large ears corn, shucked 1 First you want to use a sharp knife to cut the corn off of the cobs. It’s easier if you snap the cob in half, stand it on its end in the middle of a large bowl and cut the kernels off from top to</description></item><item><title>CORNMEAL WAFFLES WITH STRAWBERRY SYRUP</title><link>/recipes/cornmeal-waffles-with-strawberry-syrup65/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/cornmeal-waffles-with-strawberry-syrup65/</guid><description>CORNMEAL WAFFLES WITH STRAWBERRY SYRUP yields 4 BIG-ASS WAFFLES, BUT THIS VARIES DEPENDING ON ingredients 1 LB strawberries 2-4 TBL sugar Instructions 1 First, make that sweet syrup: Cut the stems off the strawberries and chop the berries into
bean-size pieces. Throw them in a small saucepan with the rest of the syrup ingredients and
warm it all over a medium-low heat. At first it might not look like there’s enough liquid to make syrup, but once everything gets going the strawberries will fix that .</description></item><item><title>CREAMY AVOCADO LIME DRESSING</title><link>/recipes/creamy-avocado-lime-dressing66/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/creamy-avocado-lime-dressing66/</guid><description>CREAMY AVOCADO LIME DRESSING yields 5 CUP (TRIPLE IT AND KEEP THIS ER IN THE FRIDGE) ingredients 1 avocado 1/3 cup lime juice 1/4 cup water 2 TBL rice vinegar 1 clove garlic 1/4 tsp ground cumin 1 pinch salt 2 TBL cilantro (optional) Instructions 1 Put all the ingredients in a blender or food processor and run it until everything looks all creamy, about 1 minute. If the dressing is too thick because you got an amazing avocado, add more water a TBL at a time until it’s less like a dip and more like a goddamn dressing.</description></item><item><title>CREAMY BLACK BEAN AND CILANTRO DIP</title><link>/recipes/creamy-black-bean-and-cilantro-dip67/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/creamy-black-bean-and-cilantro-dip67/</guid><description>CREAMY BLACK BEAN AND CILANTRO DIP yields 4 TO 6, ABOUT 3 cup ingredients 2 1/2 cup cooked black beans 1/3 cup vegetable broth or water 2 clove garlic 2 tsp lime juice 1 pinch salt 1/2 tsp chili powder 1/4 cup cilantro 1/2 cup green onions Instructions Throw all of that in a food processor and run until creamy. Or mash the everliving
out of it with a potato masher until it is the consistency you want.</description></item><item><title>CREAMY HORCHATA</title><link>/recipes/creamy-horchata68/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/creamy-horchata68/</guid><description>CREAMY HORCHATA yields 4 GLASSES ingredients 1 cup uncooked long-grain brown rice 2/3 cup raw almonds 3 cinnamon stick 4 cup water 1 TBL agave syrup or maple syrup Ice or water Ground cinnamon Instructions 1 Rinse the rice well under cool water. Throw it in a large container with a lid and add the
almonds, cinnamon stick, and water. Let this all soak together overnight or for at least 8</description></item><item><title>CREAMY PEANUT SLAW</title><link>/recipes/creamy-peanut-slaw69/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/creamy-peanut-slaw69/</guid><description>CREAMY PEANUT SLAW yields 4 AS A SIDE ingredients 3 TBL peanut butter 2 TBL warm water 3 TBL rice vinegar 2 TBL lime juice 1 TBL minced fresh ginger 1 1/2 tsp Sriracha or your favorite Asian-style hot sauce 1/2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 3 cup thinly sliced red cabbage 3 cup thinly sliced green cabbage 1 carrot, cut into thin matchsticks 1/3 cup thinly sliced green onions Instructions 1 Make the peanut dressing: Mix the peanut butter and warm water together in a medium glass until it’s creamy.</description></item><item><title>CREAMY PESTO DIP</title><link>/recipes/creamy-pesto-dip70/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/creamy-pesto-dip70/</guid><description>CREAMY PESTO DIP yields 1 CUP, ENOUGH FOR 2 TO 4 PEOPLE ingredients 3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlic * 3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlicl* 3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlic 1/4 tsp salt* 1/4 tsp salte or cannellini beans instructions 0 chop garlic 1 Place the almonds in a food processor or blender and pulse those nutty around until they start getting kinda broken up.</description></item><item><title>CREAMY RAVIOLI WITH HOUSE MARINARA</title><link>/recipes/creamy-ravioli-with-house-marinara71/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/creamy-ravioli-with-house-marinara71/</guid><description>CREAMY RAVIOLI WITH HOUSE MARINARA ingredients 2 cup all-purpose flour ½ cup flour 1 pinch salt ¾ to 1 cup water 3 TBL olive oil House Marinara Tofu Ricotta instructions 1 To make the dough: In a large bowl, combine the flours and salt and stir it all around.
Make a crater in the center of that and add ¾ cup of the water and the olive oil.</description></item><item><title>CREAMY WHITE BEAN AND ARUGULA SANDWICHES</title><link>/recipes/creamy-white-bean-and-arugula-sandwiches72/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/creamy-white-bean-and-arugula-sandwiches72/</guid><description>CREAMY WHITE BEAN AND ARUGULA SANDWICHES yields 6 SAMMIES (IF YOU PORTION YOUR FILLING OUT WITH SOME GODDAMN RESTRAINT) ingredients 3 cup cooked white or cannellini beans
1 avocado avocado
3 TBL lemon juice 0.5 red onion
1/2 cup cucumber (about .5 cucumber)* 1/2 cup cucumber (about .5 cucumber)b* 1/2 cup cucumber (about .5 cucumber)
2 clove garlic
optional *</description></item><item><title>CRISPY MILLET AND PEANUT BUTTER BUCKEYES</title><link>/recipes/crispy-millet-and-peanut-butter-buckeyes73/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/crispy-millet-and-peanut-butter-buckeyes73/</guid><description>CRISPY MILLET AND PEANUT BUTTER BUCKEYES yields 24 BUCKEYES ingredients 1/3 cup uncooked millet 2/3 cup creamy peanut butter 1/4 cup powdered sugar 2 TBL flour 1 1/2 tsp vanilla extract 1 cup semisweet chocolate chips 1 tsp butter, if needed Instructions 1 Heat the oil in a skillet over medium heat and toss in the millet. Shake the millet around in
the pan until it starts to smell toasted and look a little golden, 3 to 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Crispy Spiced Lamb and Lentils</title><link>/recipes/crispy-spiced-lamb-and-lentils74/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/crispy-spiced-lamb-and-lentils74/</guid><description>Crispy Spiced Lamb and Lentils link
yields 4 Servings ingredients 1 tablespoon vegetable oil ½ pound ground lamb 2 garlic cloves, minced ½ teaspoon cumin seeds or a heaped 1/2 teaspoon ground ½ teaspoon ground coriander 1 ½ cups cooked brown or green lentils (from a scant 1 cup dried) 8-10 cup-shaped leaves from 1 medium head bibb or butter lettuce 4 tablespoons tahini juice of 3/4 of a lemon 1 minced garlic clove 3 tablespoons water 2/3 cup plain yogurt Red pepper flakes salt black pepper instructions Make crispy lamb and lentils: Heat a large skillet over medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>CRUTONS</title><link>/recipes/crutons75/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/crutons75/</guid><description>CRUTONS ingredients 1 tsp dried thyme 1/4 tsp paprika 1/4 tsp salt Instructions 0 cube the bread (enough to make 5 cup of cubes)
1 Crank your oven to 400°F.
2 Cut up the bread into bite-size cubes. You should get around 5 cup. In a big bowl, combine
the rest of the ingredients and mix. Add the bread pieces and mix that er up to make sure</description></item><item><title>CUMIN-SPIKED PINTO BEAN DIP</title><link>/recipes/cuminspiked-pinto-bean-dip76/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/cuminspiked-pinto-bean-dip76/</guid><description>CUMIN-SPIKED PINTO BEAN DIP yields 4 TO 6, ABOUT 3.5 cup ingredients 2 tsp olive oil
1 white or yellow onion (about 1 cup) white or yellow onion (about 1 cup)
1 1/2 TBL ground cumin* 1 1/2 TBL ground cumine* 1 1/2 TBL ground cumin* 1 1/2 TBL ground cumin* 1 1/2 TBL ground cuminble broth or water
2 TBL lime juice Salt</description></item><item><title>CURRY HAND PIES WITH CILANTRO-MINT SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/curry-hand-pies-with-cilantromint-sauce77/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/curry-hand-pies-with-cilantromint-sauce77/</guid><description>CURRY HAND PIES WITH CILANTRO-MINT SAUCE yields 16 PIES (DEPENDING ON THE SIZE YOU CUT THAT ) ingredients 2 tsp olive, grapeseed, or butter 0.5 yellow onion 2 carrots 2 cup cooked yellow split peas 1 cup frozen green peas 1/2 tsp of your favorite no-salt curry powder 1/4 tsp ground cumin 1/4 tsp ground coriander 1/8 tsp cayenne pepper 2 cup spinach, cut into thin strips 2 clove garlic 2 tsp minced fresh ginger 1 TBL soy sauce or tamari 1 TBL lemon or lime juice 1 1/4 cup flour 1 cup all-purpose flour 1 TBL baking powder 1 TBL of your favorite no-salt curry powder 1/2 tsp salt 1 cup canned coconut milk Spray oil 1 1/2 piece of fresh ginger 1 jalapeño 2 cup fresh mint leaves 2 cup cilantro 1/4 cup lemon juice 1/4 cup water 1/2 tsp salt Instructions 0 chop onion, carrot, jalapeno(seeded) the size of peas; peel ginger</description></item><item><title>CURRY TEMPEH SALAD</title><link>/recipes/curry-tempeh-salad78/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/curry-tempeh-salad78/</guid><description>CURRY TEMPEH SALAD yields 4 AS A MAIN, 6 TO 8 AS A SIDE ingredients 1 TBL lime or lemon juice* 1 TBL lime or lemon juicee* 1 TBL lime or lemon juice* 1 TBL lime or lemon juice* 1 TBL lime or lemon juicea* 1 TBL lime or lemon juice
1/2 tsp Sriracha-style hot sauce
1/4 tsp salt* 1/4 tsp salth, cut into bite-size pieces ounces tempeh, cut into bite-size pieces</description></item><item><title>DEVILED CHICKPEA BITES</title><link>/recipes/deviled-chickpea-bites79/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/deviled-chickpea-bites79/</guid><description>DEVILED CHICKPEA BITES yields 18 BITES, ENOUGH FOR 4 TO 6 PEOPLE ingredients 1 1/2 cup cooked chickpeas* 1 1/2 cup cooked chickpeasn* 1 1/2 cup cooked chickpeas* 1 1/2 cup cooked chickpeas* 1 1/2 cup cooked chickpeasl* 1 1/2 cup cooked chickpeas* 1 1/2 cup cooked chickpeas* 1 1/2 cup cooked chickpeasnal yeast
1 1/4 tsp Dijon mustard* 1 1/4 tsp Dijon mustard
0.</description></item><item><title>ENCHILADA-ISH SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/enchiladaish-sauce80/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/enchiladaish-sauce80/</guid><description>ENCHILADA-ISH SAUCE yields 9 X 13-INCH PAN, ENOUGH FOR 6 TO 8 PEOPLE ingredients 1 ½ cup vegetable broth 1 ½ cup plain tomato sauce 2 clove garlic 3 TBL mild chili powder 2 TBL lime juice 1 TBL soy sauce or tamari ½ tsp ground cumin ½ tsp dried oregano 2 tsp olive oil 1 medium yellow onion 1 red bell pepper 3 clove garlic 1 jalapeño, minced 3 cup cooked black beans 1 cup fresh or frozen corn kernels 1 ½ tsp chili powder ½ tsp ground cumin ½ tsp smoked paprika ½ tsp salt 1 ½ cup canned pumpkin puree 1 TBL lime juice 2 tsp maple syrup 12 flour tortillas Salsa (any of the from our first book would be legit) Avocado instructions 0 chop onion and bell pepper 1 First, make the enchilada-ish sauce: Pour everything together in a medium saucepan and bring it to a gentle simmer—not a boil, a goddamn simmer—and cook for about 15 minutes to give the sauce a chance to thicken up a little.</description></item><item><title>EVERYDAY GUACAMOLE</title><link>/recipes/everyday-guacamole81/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/everyday-guacamole81/</guid><description>EVERYDAY GUACAMOLE yields 5 cup, DEPENDING ON THE SIZE OF YOUR AVOCADOS ingredients 2 avocados, preferably Hass avocados, preferably Hass
1/4 cup diced red or white onion* 1/4 cup diced red or white onion
1 jalapeño or Fresno pepper, minced jalapeño or Fresno pepper, minced
1 tsp lime juice* 1 tsp lime juice * 1 tsp lime juice
1 pinch salt</description></item><item><title>FAMILY-STYLE ROASTED VEGGIE PASTA</title><link>/recipes/familystyle-roasted-veggie-pasta82/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/familystyle-roasted-veggie-pasta82/</guid><description>FAMILY-STYLE ROASTED VEGGIE PASTA yields 4 TO 6 PEOPLE ingredients 1 LB pasta 1 TBL olive oil, plus more if needed for the pasta ½ large red onion, sliced 2 medium carrots, cut into thin matchsticks 1 pint tiny tomatoes, halved 1 medium zucchini, cut into thin matchsticks 1 LB eggplant ¼ tsp salt 2 ½ TBL fresh thyme leaves 3 clove garlic 2 TBL lemon juice 3 TBL balsamic vinegar ½ tsp red pepper flakes (Optional) Salt and black pepper instructions cube eggplant 1 Cook the pasta according to the package directions.</description></item><item><title>FIRE-ROASTED SALSA</title><link>/recipes/fireroasted-salsa83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/fireroasted-salsa83/</guid><description>FIRE-ROASTED SALSA yields 4 TO 6, ABOUT 2.5 cup ingredients 1 can (14.5 ounces) fire-roasted diced tomatoes can (14.5 ounces) fire-roasted diced tomatoes 0.5 white onion
1/3 cup green onions* 1/3 cup green onionsro
3 serrano peppers serrano peppers
8 clove roasted garlic* 8 clove roasted garlic * 8 clove roasted garlic
1 tsp lime juice
Salt to taste</description></item><item><title>FOUR-BEAN SALAD</title><link>/recipes/fourbean-salad84/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/fourbean-salad84/</guid><description>FOUR-BEAN SALAD yields 6 TO 8 PEOPLE AS A SMALL SIDE ingredients 1 clove garlic 2 TBL lemon juice 2 TBL rice vinegar 3 TBL apple cider vinegar 1/4 cup olive oil 0.5 LB green beans, cut into 1-inch pieces 1 1/2 cup each cooked chickpeas, kidney beans, and cannellini beans 1 1/4 cup celery 1/2 medium red onion, cut into 1-inch pieces 1/2 cup fresh parsley 1/2 tsp garlic powder 1/2 tsp celery seed 1/4 tsp salt Black pepper Instructions 1 Make the dressing: Throw the mustard, sweetener, garlic, lemon juice, vinegars, and olive oil together in a small jar and shake the out of it.</description></item><item><title>FRESH CORN BUTTER PIE</title><link>/recipes/fresh-corn-butter-pie85/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/fresh-corn-butter-pie85/</guid><description>FRESH CORN BUTTER PIE yields 1 PIE ingredients 3 cup corn kernels* 3 cup corn kernelst* 3 cup corn kernels* 3 cup corn kernels* 3 cup corn kernelsextract
1/4 tsp salt Whipped Cream optional
instructions 0 cut corn kernels off the cob. 1 Make the pie crust through step 3. Let it chill out in the fridge while you make the filling. Also, start cranking your oven up to 425°F.</description></item><item><title>FRUIT SALAD SMOOTHIE</title><link>/recipes/fruit-salad-smoothie87/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/fruit-salad-smoothie87/</guid><description>FRUIT SALAD SMOOTHIE yields 1 SMOOTHIE ingredients 2 cup fresh spinach 1 1/2 bananas 1 cup tap or coconut water 1/2 cup orange juice 1/2 cup frozen strawberries 1/4 cup frozen blueberries Instructions cut bananas into pieces each about 1.5 inches long and freeze 1 Throw all that in a blender and let it do its thing. Taste and add more of whatever you want. If
you want it thicker, add more banana.</description></item><item><title>FUDGY-AS- BROWNIES</title><link>/recipes/fudgyasfuck-brownies88/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/fudgyasfuck-brownies88/</guid><description>FUDGY-AS- BROWNIES yields 16 BROWNIES, IF YOU CUT UP IN A REASONABLE SIZE ingredients 2 TBL ground flax seeds* 2 TBL ground flax seedsc* 2 TBL ground flax seeds* 2 TBL ground flax seeds* 2 TBL ground flax seeds* 2 TBL ground flax seeds* 2 TBL ground flax seeds* 2 TBL ground flax seeds* 2 TBL ground flax seeds* 2 TBL ground flax seeds* 2 TBL ground flax seeds soda</description></item><item><title>GINGER-LIME SPARKLERS</title><link>/recipes/gingerlime-sparklers89/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/gingerlime-sparklers89/</guid><description>GINGER-LIME SPARKLERS yields 4 ingredients 1 lime, cut into small wedges lime, cut into small wedges 1 1/2 TBL minced fresh peeled ginger* 1 1/2 TBL minced fresh peeled ginger * 1 1/2 TBL minced fresh peeled ginger* 1 1/2 TBL minced fresh peeled ginger 3 cup tonic water instructions 1 Grab your blender and throw the lime wedges, ginger, sugar, and 1 cup of the water right in.</description></item><item><title>GINGER-SESAME MARINADE</title><link>/recipes/gingersesame-marinade91/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/gingersesame-marinade91/</guid><description>GINGER-SESAME MARINADE ingredients 2 TBL lime juice 2 TBL brown sugar 1 TBL minced fresh ginger 2 tsp toasted sesame oil 2 tsp Sriracha or similar hot sauce 2 clove garlic, thickly sliced Instructions 1 Combine all ingredients</description></item><item><title>GRILLED ARTICHOKES WITH ROASTED GARLIC DIP</title><link>/recipes/grilled-artichokes-with-roasted-garlic-dip92/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/grilled-artichokes-with-roasted-garlic-dip92/</guid><description>GRILLED ARTICHOKES WITH ROASTED GARLIC DIP yields 4 PEOPLE ingredients 2 lemons Salt 4 clove garlic, 2 smashed and 2 minced 2 large artichokes 1/4 cup olive oil Roasted Garlic Dip Instructions 1 Fill a large pot with water and put it over high heat. Squeeze the juice of .5 lemon into the pot and slice up the other half and add it to the water with a good pinch of salt and the 2 clove of smashed garlic.</description></item><item><title>GRILLED EGGPLANT WITH SOBA NOODLES</title><link>/recipes/grilled-eggplant-with-soba-noodles93/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/grilled-eggplant-with-soba-noodles93/</guid><description>GRILLED EGGPLANT WITH SOBA NOODLES yields 4 PEOPLE OR JUST 1 IF YOU WANT TO SAVE THIS ingredients 2 TBL toasted se title: &amp;ldquo;GRILLED EGGPLANT WITH SOBA NOODLES&amp;rdquo; tags:
recipe GRILLED EGGPLANT WITH SOBA NOODLES yields 4 PEOPLE OR JUST 1 IF YOU WANT TO SAVE THIS ingredients 2 TBL toasted seg for the marinade in a glass. Slice the eggplant crosswise into .</description></item><item><title>GRILLED PEACH SALSA</title><link>/recipes/grilled-peach-salsa94/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/grilled-peach-salsa94/</guid><description>GRILLED PEACH SALSA yields 4 TO 6, ABOUT 3.5 cup ingredients 3 LB peaches 1/2 tsp oil 1 to 2 serrano peppers, minced 1/2 medium red onion 1 medium tomato 1/4 cup lime juice 1/4 tsp salt Handful of cilantro Instructions 0 chop onion (about 2⁄3 cup) and tomato
1 Cut the peaches into wedges no thicker than an inch. You can leave the skin on because
everybody needs more fiber in their mother diet.</description></item><item><title>GRILLED PINEAPPLE AND SWEET-AND-SOUR TEMPEH KEBABS</title><link>/recipes/grilled-pineapple-and-sweetandsour-tempeh-kebabs95/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/grilled-pineapple-and-sweetandsour-tempeh-kebabs95/</guid><description>GRILLED PINEAPPLE AND SWEET-AND-SOUR TEMPEH KEBABS yields 10 KEBABS, ENOUGH FOR 5 PEOPLE ingredients 2 TBL water* 2 TBL waterc* 2 TBL water* 2 TBL water* 2 TBL wateri* 2 TBL water* 2 TBL water* 2 TBL waterg* 2 TBL water* 2 TBL water
2 tsp soy sauce or tamari* 2 tsp soy sauce or tamari * 2 tsp soy sauce or tamari* 2 tsp soy sauce or tamari</description></item><item><title>GRILLED VEGGIE AND TEMPEH KEBABS WITH CHIMICHURRI SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/grilled-veggie-and-tempeh-kebabs-with-chimichurri-sauce96/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/grilled-veggie-and-tempeh-kebabs-with-chimichurri-sauce96/</guid><description>GRILLED VEGGIE AND TEMPEH KEBABS WITH CHIMICHURRI SAUCE yields 10 KEBABS, ENOUGH FOR 5 PEOPLE ingredients 1 cup fresh flat-leaf parsley 1/4 cup shallot or white onion 1/4 cup olive oil 3 TBL red wine vinegar 2 TBL water 1 TBL lemon juice 1 TBL fresh oregano 3 clove garlic 1 serrano pepper, seeded and chopped 1/4 tsp salt 8 ounces tempeh, cut into large cubes 1/2 cup vegetable broth 1 TBL soy sauce or tamari 1 TBL liquid smoke 1 TBL olive or grapeseed oil 2 small zucchini or yellow squash 0.</description></item><item><title>GRITS AND SWEET POTATO BREAKFAST CASSEROLE</title><link>/recipes/grits-and-sweet-potato-breakfast-casserole97/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/grits-and-sweet-potato-breakfast-casserole97/</guid><description>GRITS AND SWEET POTATO BREAKFAST CASSEROLE yields 9 X 13-INCH CASSEROLE, ENOUGH FOR 6 TO 8 PEOPLE ingredients 1 TBL olive oil 0.5 yellow onion, sliced
1 1/2 cup grated raw sweet potato* 1 1/2 cup grated raw sweet potatow squash or zucchini, grated
1 red bell pepper red bell pepper
2 cup spinach* 2 cup spinach* 2 cup spinach* 2 cup spinach* 2 cup spinach* 2 cup spinach* 2 cup spinach* 2 cup spinachpepper</description></item><item><title>HIGH SCHOOL–STYLE HARD LEMONADE</title><link>/recipes/high-schoolstyle-hard-lemonade98/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/high-schoolstyle-hard-lemonade98/</guid><description>HIGH SCHOOL–STYLE HARD LEMONADE yields 1 QUART ingredients 5 cup water 0.5 to ¾ cup sugar 3/4 cup lemon juice (about 6 lemons) 1 tsp lime juice 1/2 cup vodka, or more if reasons Lemon wedges and mint sprigs, for garnish Instructions 1 In a medium pot, bring the water to a boil over medium-high heat. Add .5 cup sugar and simmer that over low heat for about 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>HOMEMADE TORTILLAS WITH MIXED FRUIT COMPOTE</title><link>/recipes/homemade-tortillas-with-mixed-fruit-compote99/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/homemade-tortillas-with-mixed-fruit-compote99/</guid><description>HOMEMADE TORTILLAS WITH MIXED FRUIT COMPOTE yields 8 TO 12 TORTILLAS ingredients 2 cup flour (whole wheat pastry, whole wheat, or all-purpose)* 2 cup flour (whole wheat pastry, whole wheat, or all-purpose)* 2 cup flour (whole wheat pastry, whole wheat, or all-purpose)* 2 cup flour (whole wheat pastry, whole wheat, or all-purpose)* 2 cup flour (whole wheat pastry, whole wheat, or all-purpose)* 2 cup flour (whole wheat pastry, whole wheat, or all-purpose)* 2 cup flour (whole wheat pastry, whole wheat, or all-purpose)* 2 cup flour (whole wheat pastry, whole wheat, or all-purpose)favorite fresh or frozen berries (chopped into bite-size pieces if necessary)</description></item><item><title>HOUSE MARINARA</title><link>/recipes/house-marinara100/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/house-marinara100/</guid><description>HOUSE MARINARA yields 4 cup ingredients 1/2 large onion 1 carrot 3 clove garlic 1 tsp olive oil 1 tsp dried thyme 1 pinch of red pepper flakes 1 can (28 ounces) whole tomatoes Salt Instructions 1 Chop up the onion. Dice up the carrot into pieces about the size of a pea. Mince the garlic
up small. You can do this in your sleep.
2 Heat the oil in a medium soup pot over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Indian Spiced Cauliflower Soup</title><link>/recipes/indian-spiced-cauliflower-soup101/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/indian-spiced-cauliflower-soup101/</guid><description>Indian Spiced Cauliflower Soup yields 4 portions ingredients 2 tablespoons olive or peanut oil ½ teaspoon whole cumin seeds ¼ teaspoon whole fennel seeds 1 medium onion, peeled and chopped 1 medium potato (about 6 ounces), peeled and chopped 2 teaspoons peeled and chopped fresh ginger 2 cloves garlic, peeled and chopped 1 fresh hot green chili, chopped (more or less to taste) 2 teaspoons ground coriander 1 teaspoon ground cumin ¼ teaspoon ground turmeric ¼ teaspoon red chili powder or cayenne (to taste) About 3 1/2 cups cauliflower florets (from about 1/2 a large 2.</description></item><item><title>ITALIAN COUSCOUS CASSEROLE</title><link>/recipes/italian-couscous-casserole102/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/italian-couscous-casserole102/</guid><description>ITALIAN COUSCOUS CASSEROLE yields 6 PEOPLE, NO PROBLEM ingredients 2 tsp olive oil 1 medium eggplant, unpeeled, cut into chunks (about 3 cup) 1 medium yellow onion 1 medium yellow squash or zucchini, shredded (about 1.5 cup) 2 clove garlic 2 tsp dried thyme 2 tsp dried basil 0.25 teapsoon red pepper flakes (optional) 2 cup spinach 1/2 tsp salt 3 cup cooked couscous (1.25 cup uncooked) Blender Red Sauce 2 TBL red wine vinegar 2 TBL lemon juice 1/2 cup nutritional yeast fresh basil or parsley for garnish (optional) Instructions 0 chop onion</description></item><item><title>ITALIAN DRESSING</title><link>/recipes/italian-dressing103/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/italian-dressing103/</guid><description>ITALIAN DRESSING yields 1 CUP ingredients 2 TBL lemon juice 2 clove garlic 3/4 tsp dried basil 3/4 tsp dried thyme 3/4 tsp onion powder Black pepper Instructions In a small jar, combine the oil, vinegar, lemon juice, garlic, dried basil, thyme, onion powder, and pepper and mix that up.</description></item><item><title>ITALIAN-STYLE PASTA SALAD</title><link>/recipes/italianstyle-pasta-salad104/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/italianstyle-pasta-salad104/</guid><description>ITALIAN-STYLE PASTA SALAD yields 4 TO 6 PEOPLE ingredients 1 LB pasta 1 small crown of broccoli 1 red bell pepper 1 cup cucumber (about .5 cucumber) 1 pint cherry or grape tomatoes, halved 1/2 cup sliced red onion (about .5 small) 1/3 cup fresh basil 1/4 cup sliced black olives (optional) 1/2 tsp salt Black pepper Instructions 0 chop broccoli and bell pepper(roasted or raw)
1 Make the dressing and set aside.</description></item><item><title>LANDLOCKED CEVICHE</title><link>/recipes/landlocked-ceviche105/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/landlocked-ceviche105/</guid><description>LANDLOCKED CEVICHE yields 4 TO 6 PEOPLE ingredients 1 small head of cauliflower 2 cup diced tomatoes (about 4 medium) 1/2 cup red onion 1 jalapeño 1/4 tsp salt 1/2 cup lime juice 1/4 cup cilantro 1 avocado Black pepper, to taste Instructions 0 chop cauliflower into tiny-ass bites (about 2.5 cup). Dice jalapeno and avacodo
1 In a medium bowl, mix together the cauliflower, tomatoes, red onion, jalapeño, salt, and lime juice.</description></item><item><title>LAZY-MORNING FRITTATA</title><link>/recipes/lazymorning-frittata106/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/lazymorning-frittata106/</guid><description>LAZY-MORNING FRITTATA yields 4 TO 6 PEOPLE ingredients 1 TBL olive oil* 1 TBL olive oilw onion
2 red bell peppers red bell peppers
1 1/2 cup broccoli* 1 1/2 cup broccolir* 1 1/2 cup broccoli* 1 1/2 cup broccoli* 1 1/2 cup broccoli* 1 1/2 cup broccoli* 1 1/2 cup broccoli* 1 1/2 cup broccolisil
1 tsp dried thyme* 1 tsp dried thymeoregano</description></item><item><title>LEMON-MINT QUINOA</title><link>/recipes/lemonmint-quinoa107/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/lemonmint-quinoa107/</guid><description>LEMON-MINT QUINOA yields 4 AS A SIDE ingredients 1 tsp plus 2 TBL olive oil 1 1/2 cup quinoa cup water 1/4 tsp salt 1/2 tsp grated lemon zest 2 TBL lemon juice 1 1/2 TBL rice vinegar 1/3 cup fresh mint 2 TBL minced green onions 1/2 cup slivered almonds, toasted (optional) Instructions 1 Grab a medium saucepan with a lid and heat 1 tsp of the oil over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>LEMONY RED LENTIL SOUP</title><link>/recipes/lemony-red-lentil-soup108/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/lemony-red-lentil-soup108/</guid><description>LEMONY RED LENTIL SOUP yields 4 AS A MAIN AND 6 AS A SIDE ingredients 1 tsp olive oil 0.5 yellow onion 1 russet potato 1 carrot 2 clove garlic 1 tsp ground coriander ½ tsp ground cumin ¼ tsp salt 2 cup red lentils, rinsed 6 cup vegetable broth ½ tsp grated lemon zest 1 TBL lemon juice ½ cup fresh cilantro (Optional) Instructions 0 chop onion and carrot; peel and dice potato</description></item><item><title>LENTIL TACOS WITH CARROT-JICAMA SLAW</title><link>/recipes/lentil-tacos-with-carrotjicama-slaw109/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/lentil-tacos-with-carrotjicama-slaw109/</guid><description>LENTIL TACOS WITH CARROT-JICAMA SLAW yields 6 TO 8 TACOS ingredients 3 cup water 1 cup black lentils, rinsed 1/2 tsp olive oil 0.5 onion 8 ounces mushrooms, cut into bite-size pieces 1 TBL soy sauce or tamari 2 or 3 clove garlic 2 TBL apple juice 1 tsp toasted sesame oil CARROT-JICAMA SLAW 0.5 LB jicama 1 small cucumber 1 carrot 2 TBL rice vinegar 1 TBL lime juice 1/4 tsp salt Sweet Fresh Herb Salsa Instructions 0 chop onion</description></item><item><title>LIGHTS OUT BLOODY MARY BAR</title><link>/recipes/lights-out-bloody-mary-bar110/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/lights-out-bloody-mary-bar110/</guid><description>LIGHTS OUT BLOODY MARY BAR yields 4 PEOPLE ingredients 4 cup tomato juice or a veggie blend 1 TBL Tabasco sauce ½ cup lemon juice 1 tsp soy sauce Black pepper 1 cup vodka ¼ cup flaky sea salt 1 tsp celery seed 1 tsp Old Bay seasoning ADD-INS Lemon wedges celery sticks cucumber sticks bell pepper sticks dill pickle spears green beans horseradish carrot sticks Ice instructions 1 In a large pitcher or old glass juice jar, mix together the tomato juice, Tabasco, lemon juice, Bragg’s, and a couple dashes of black pepper.</description></item><item><title>LOADED NACHOS</title><link>/recipes/loaded-nachos111/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/loaded-nachos111/</guid><description>LOADED NACHOS yields enough for 4 TO 6 PEOPLE 4 to 5 handfuls warm tortilla chips 1 ½ cup cooked black beans 1 cup thinly sliced cabbage or romaine lettuce Butternut Squash Queso-ish Dip Everyday Guacamole Your favorite chunky-style salsa 1 jalapeño, sliced into thin circles ¼ cup cilantro Hot sauce (Optional) Instructions 1 You know how nachos work, so you can pile this on however you like and leave off or add whatever the you want.</description></item><item><title>LOW-FAT FARMHOUSE DIP</title><link>/recipes/lowfat-farmhouse-dip112/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/lowfat-farmhouse-dip112/</guid><description>LOW-FAT FARMHOUSE DIP yields 5 cup, ENOUGH FOR 6 TO 8 PEOPLE ingredients 12 ounces soft silken tofu ounces soft silken tofu
2 TBL minced shallot or white onion* 2 TBL minced shallot or white onion* 2 TBL minced shallot or white onion* 2 TBL minced shallot or white onion* 2 TBL minced shallot or white onionc* 2 TBL minced shallot or white onion
1/2 tsp salt</description></item><item><title>MANGO CURRY</title><link>/recipes/mango-curry113/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/mango-curry113/</guid><description>MANGO CURRY yields 4 ingredients 1 tsp coconut or grapeseed oil 0.5 onion
1 1/2 cup green beans cut into 1-inch pieces* 1 1/2 cup green beans cut into 1-inch piecesini, cut into .125-inch half-moons
1 bell pepper bell pepper
3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlice* 3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlice* 3 clove garlic
1 1/2 cup canned coconut milk</description></item><item><title>MAPLE BERRY GRITS</title><link>/recipes/maple-berry-grits114/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/maple-berry-grits114/</guid><description>MAPLE BERRY GRITS yields 4 DAYS ingredients 2 cup water 2 cup almond or other nondairy milk 1 cup stoneground grits ¼-½ tsp salt 1-2 tsp maple syrup jam Fresh berries instructions 1 Grab a medium saucepan and bring the water and milk to a boil over medium heat. Gently whisk in the grits and .25 tsp salt. Don’t just dump it all in and spill water everywhere— show some care, man.</description></item><item><title>MAPLE-OAT BANANA BREAD</title><link>/recipes/mapleoat-banana-bread115/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/mapleoat-banana-bread115/</guid><description>MAPLE-OAT BANANA BREAD ingredients 2 cup oat flour* 2 cup oat flour
tsp baking soda
3/4 tsp ground cinnamon* 3/4 tsp ground cinnamon* 3/4 tsp ground cinnamon* 3/4 tsp ground cinnamon* 3/4 tsp ground cinnamonc* 3/4 tsp ground cinnamon* 3/4 tsp ground cinnamon* 3/4 tsp ground cinnamons* 3/4 tsp ground cinnamon
3 TBL olive oil
1 tsp vanilla extract* 1 tsp vanilla extract</description></item><item><title>MEATBALL SUBS</title><link>/recipes/meatball-subs116/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/meatball-subs116/</guid><description>MEATBALL SUBS yields 6 SUBS (ABOUT 24 MEATBALLS, IF YOU DO THAT RIGHT) ingredients 1 1/2 cup cooked kidney beans 1 1/2 cup cooked brown lentils 1/4 cup onion 1/3 cup whole wheat bread crumbs 3 clove garlic 1/4 cup nutritional yeast or flour 2 TBL olive oil 1 TBL soy sauce or tamari 2 tsp seasoning blend 1/2 tsp dried oregano 1/2 tsp dried thyme 1/2 tsp grated lemon zest Quick Blender Marinara 2 baguettes Arugula, for serving Instructions 1 Crank your oven to 400°F.</description></item><item><title>MELON AND MINT FRUIT SALAD</title><link>/recipes/melon-and-mint-fruit-salad118/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/melon-and-mint-fruit-salad118/</guid><description>MELON AND MINT FRUIT SALAD yields 6 PEOPLE ingredients 2 small melons* 2 small melons * 2 small melons* 2 small melons 1 TBL minced fresh mint instructions 0 chop melons into chunks no bigger than a nickel (about 10 cup) 1 Mix the melon, lemon zest, sugar, and mint together in a big ass bowl. Let this chill in the fridge for a minimum of 2 hours, or you can let it hang out overnight.</description></item><item><title>MICHELADA</title><link>/recipes/michelada119/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/michelada119/</guid><description>MICHELADA yields 4 PEOPLE ingredients 4 cup of your favorite light beer 1/4 cup lime juice 2 tsp of your favorite taqueria-style hot sauce 1 tsp soy sauce or tamari FANCY RIM (optional) 1 TBL sea salt 1 tsp chili powder 0.5 lime, plus lime wedges Instructions 1 Mix the beer, lime juice, hot sauce, and soy sauce or tamari in a large container.
2 For the optional fancy rim: Grab a plate and mix the salt and chili powder together.</description></item><item><title>MID-SUMMER SALSA</title><link>/recipes/midsummer-salsa120/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/midsummer-salsa120/</guid><description>MID-SUMMER SALSA yields 4 TO 6, ABOUT 4.5 cup ingredients 1 LB tomatoes 0.5 white onion
2 to 3 clove garlic to 3 clove garlic* 2 to 3 clove garlic to 3 clove garlicapeño
2 TBL lime juice
optional *
1 TBL orange juice
1/4 cup cilantro* 1/4 cup cilantro
instructions 0 chop onion and tomatoes. dice jalapeno 1 If you’re a picky mother er about salsa, you’ve got a couple options here.</description></item><item><title>MIXED MUSHROOM AND SPINACH</title><link>/recipes/mixed-mushroom-and-spinach121/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/mixed-mushroom-and-spinach121/</guid><description>MIXED MUSHROOM AND SPINACH yields 6 TO 8 PEOPLE AT ONCE OR YOUR SINGLE ASS ingredients 1/3 cup slivered or sliced almonds 1 1/4 cup packed torn basil leaves 2 TBL olive oil 2 TBL water 1 TBL lemon juice 1/2 tsp grated lemon zest 1/2 tsp salt 2 to 3 clove garlic 16 ounces button or cremini mushrooms 1 tsp olive oil 6 cup spinach Salt 1 LB lasagna noodles Double batch of House Marinara Double batch of Tofu Ricotta Sliced tomatoes (optional) Instructions 0 chop garlic</description></item><item><title>MIXED VEGGIE AND TOFU CHILAQUILES</title><link>/recipes/mixed-veggie-and-tofu-chilaquiles122/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/mixed-veggie-and-tofu-chilaquiles122/</guid><description>MIXED VEGGIE AND TOFU CHILAQUILES yields 4 TO 6 ingredients 12 corn tortillas 2 tsp olive oil 1 block medium-firm tofu 2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 1 tsp garlic powder 1/4 cup nutritional yeast 1/2 medium onion 1 bell pepper 1-2 jalapeños 2 clove garlic 2-3 cup fresh spinach 2 1/2 cup salsa verde 1/4 cup vegetable broth 1 avocado (optional) 1 cilantro (optional) 1 jalapeño (optional) 1 pico de gallo (optional) Instructions 0 chop the onion and bell pepper and jalapenos.</description></item><item><title>MOROCCAN SPICED COUSCOUS</title><link>/recipes/moroccan-spiced-couscous123/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/moroccan-spiced-couscous123/</guid><description>MOROCCAN SPICED COUSCOUS yields 2 TO 4 AS A SIDE ingredients 1 cup orange segments Instructions 1 Mix the couscous, salt, and spices in a medium saucepot with a tight-fitting lid. Add the
boiling water to the couscous mix without splashing it around and burning the out of
your hand. Stir everything up and quickly put on the lid. Let it rest for at least 8 minutes. The</description></item><item><title>MULLED SPIKED CIDER</title><link>/recipes/mulled-spiked-cider124/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/mulled-spiked-cider124/</guid><description>MULLED SPIKED CIDER yields 4 PEOPLE ingredients 5 cup apple cider or juice
1 orange, cut into slices orange, cut into slices* 1 orange, cut into slices orange, cut into slices * 1 orange, cut into slices orange, cut into slices
3 cinnamon sticks cinnamon sticks
1/4 tsp ground allspice* 1/4 tsp ground allspiceourbon
instructions 1 In a large pot, combine the cider, orange slices, ginger, cinnamon sticks, and allspice and bring to a simmer over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>OAT FLOUR GRIDDLE CAKES WITH BLUEBERRY SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/oat-flour-griddle-cakes-with-blueberry-sauce126/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/oat-flour-griddle-cakes-with-blueberry-sauce126/</guid><description>OAT FLOUR GRIDDLE CAKES WITH BLUEBERRY SAUCE yields 8 TO 10 GRIDDLE CAKES ingredients 1 1/2 cup rolled oats 2 TBL ground flaxseed 1 1/2 cup plain almond or other nondairy milk 1/2 cup oat flour 1 TBL sugar 1 1/2 tsp baking powder 1/2 tsp salt 1/2 tsp ground cinnamon 1 TBL butter Blueberry Sauce (recipe opposite) Instructions 1 In a large bowl, mix together the oats, ground flaxseed, and almond milk.</description></item><item><title>PAD THAI ROLLS</title><link>/recipes/pad-thai-rolls127/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/pad-thai-rolls127/</guid><description>PAD THAI ROLLS yields 12 ROLLS THAT WILL HAVE PEOPLE TALKING FOR WEEKS ingredients 2 TBL sugar* 2 TBL sugara* 2 TBL sugar* 2 TBL sugar* 2 TBL sugarce
1/2 cup peanuts* 1/2 cup peanuts5 ounces) maifun, glass noodles, or thin rice noodles package (6.75 ounces) maifun, glass noodles, or thin rice noodles
1 1/2 tsp soy sauce or tamari* 1 1/2 tsp soy sauce or tamaris* 1 1/2 tsp soy sauce or tamari</description></item><item><title>PAN-ROASTED PEPPERS</title><link>/recipes/panroasted-peppers128/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/panroasted-peppers128/</guid><description>PAN-ROASTED PEPPERS ingredients 1 pinch salt Instructions 1 Grab a large wok or skillet and heat up 1 TBL of the oil over high heat. Throw in half the peppers and stir them around every now and then. Keep cooking until the skins on the peppers look black in some places and they are starting to soften, about 5 minutes. Throw them in a medium bowl and repeat with the remaining peppers and oil.</description></item><item><title>PANZANELLA</title><link>/recipes/panzanella129/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/panzanella129/</guid><description>PANZANELLA yields 4 TO 6 PEOPLE NO PROBLEM, OR ONE LEGIT BOWL FOR A PICNIC ingredients 2 TBL lemon juice 2 clove garlic 1/4 cup olive oil 1/2 loaf stale crusty bread, cut into bite-size cubes (about 6 cup) 1 cup cooked quinoa 1/2 small red onion, sliced 2 cup halved cherry or grape tomatoes 1 1/2 cup bite-size pieces of cucumber 1 red bell pepper 1/2 cup packed sliced fresh basil 1 cup fresh parsley 1/4 tsp salt Black pepper Instructions 0 chop bell peppers and parsley</description></item><item><title>PEACH JULEPS</title><link>/recipes/peach-juleps130/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/peach-juleps130/</guid><description>PEACH JULEPS ingredients 10 fresh mint leaves 1 tsp sugar ½ cup peach puree ¼ cup bourbon 1 TBL lemon or lime juice Ice 2 cup sparkling water Mint sprigs or sliced peaches, for garnish Instructions 1 Add the mint leaves and sugar to the bottom of a big pitcher or jar and mash them around with the back of a spoon to try and break down the mint a little bit.</description></item><item><title>PEACH-MINT SUN TEA</title><link>/recipes/peachmint-sun-tea131/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/peachmint-sun-tea131/</guid><description>PEACH-MINT SUN TEA ingredients 4 cup cold water 4 bags of your favorite black tea 2 ripe peaches 2 TBL lemon juice 10 mint leaves, plus mint sprigs for garnish 2 tsp agave or maple syrup (Optional) Ice Instructions chop peaches into chunks 1 Place the water and tea bags in a large container with a lid and set that er in the sun for 3
to 5 hours.</description></item><item><title>PEACHY ALMOND TAPIOCA PUDDING</title><link>/recipes/peachy-almond-tapioca-pudding132/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/peachy-almond-tapioca-pudding132/</guid><description>PEACHY ALMOND TAPIOCA PUDDING yields 4 NORMAL PEOPLE ingredients 2 cup water yields 4 NORMAL PEOPLE ingredients 2 cup water hours, though. gets weird after that.
2 When you are ready to cook, drain the tapioca pearls. Put them in a medium saucepan with
the juice, almond milk, salt, and vanilla. If your juice isn’t super sweet, then go ahead and add
the agave. Just taste it and you will figure it out.</description></item><item><title>PEANUT BUTTER AND BANANA NUT MUFFINS</title><link>/recipes/peanut-butter-and-banana-nut-muffins133/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/peanut-butter-and-banana-nut-muffins133/</guid><description>PEANUT BUTTER AND BANANA NUT MUFFINS yields 12 STANDARD MUFFINS ingredients 2 cup whole wheat pastry or all-purpose flour 1 TBL baking powder 1/2 tsp salt 1/2 cup creamy peanut butter 1/2 cup packed light brown sugar 3/4 cup plain almond or other nondairy milk 1 1/2 cup mashed ripe banana 1 tsp vanilla extract 1/2 cup walnuts or peanuts Instructions 1 Heat your oven to 375°F. Grease your muffin tin or use paper muffin liners.</description></item><item><title>PEAR AND POPPY SEED LB CAKE</title><link>/recipes/pear-and-poppy-seed-lb-cake134/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/pear-and-poppy-seed-lb-cake134/</guid><description>PEAR AND POPPY SEED LB CAKE yields 1 LOAF ingredients 1 tsp vanilla extract 1 tsp almond extract 2 cup flour 2 tsp baking powder 2 tsp poppy seeds 1/4 tsp ground cardamom 1 1/4 cup grated pear (about 1 big one) Instructions 1 Warm up the oven to 350°F. Lightly grease a 9 x -5-inch loaf pan.
2 Throw the butter and the sugar together in a medium bowl.</description></item><item><title>PINEAPPLE GUACAMOLE</title><link>/recipes/pineapple-guacamole135/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/pineapple-guacamole135/</guid><description>PINEAPPLE GUACAMOLE yields 4 TO 6, ABOUT 2.5 cup ingredients 2 avocados 2/3 cup pineapple 1/2 cup red onion 2 TBL cilantro 2 to 3 clove garlic Grated zest of .5 lime 1 TBL lime juice 1/8 tsp ground cumin 1 pinch salt Instructions 1 Mash up the avocado into nice chunks. Add everything to the avocado and stir. Taste and add
more of your favorite . Serve at room temp or chill.</description></item><item><title>PIÑA COLADA ICEES</title><link>/recipes/pia-colada-icees136/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/pia-colada-icees136/</guid><description>PIÑA COLADA ICEES yields 5 cup, ENOUGH FOR 2 TO 4 PEOPLE ingredients 2 cup ice cubes 1 1/2 cup frozen pineapple chunks 1 1/2 cup pineapple juice 3/4 cup white rum 1/2 cup canned coconut milk 2 bananas, broken into chunks and frozen 2 TBL agave syrup or your favorite liquid sweetener Instructions Throw everything in a blender that can handle some ice and let that run until your drink as is smooth as you imagine yourself being after you drink it.</description></item><item><title>POPPY SEED POTATO SALAD</title><link>/recipes/poppy-seed-potato-salad137/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/poppy-seed-potato-salad137/</guid><description>POPPY SEED POTATO SALAD yields 6 PEOPLE, OR A BIG-ASS BOWL AT A PICNIC ingredients 1 TBL Dijon mustard* 1 TBL Dijon mustarde* 1 TBL Dijon mustard* 1 TBL Dijon mustard
1 pinch salt* 1 pinch saltribs celery
2 medium carrots, shredded (about 1 cup)* 2 medium carrots, shredded (about 1 cup) * 2 medium carrots, shredded (about 1 cup)
1/4 tsp salt</description></item><item><title>POPPY SEED PROTEIN WAFFLES</title><link>/recipes/poppy-seed-protein-waffles138/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/poppy-seed-protein-waffles138/</guid><description>POPPY SEED PROTEIN WAFFLES yields 4 BIG-ASS WAFFLES, BUT THIS VARIES DEPENDING ON YOUR WAFFLE MAKER ingredients 12 ounces soft silken tofu 1 1/2 cup nondairy milk, such as almond 1 TBL vanilla extract Grated zest of 1 lemon (about 1 TBL) 2 TBL lemon juice 2 cup flour 1/4 cup sugar 2 tsp baking powder 1 tsp baking soda 1/2 tsp salt 2 TBL poppy seeds Spray oil Maple syrup, seasonal fruit Instructions 1 Warm up the waffle iron.</description></item><item><title>Pork Chops With Apples and Cider</title><link>/recipes/pork-chops-with-apples-and-cider139/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/pork-chops-with-apples-and-cider139/</guid><description>Pork Chops With Apples and Cider yields 4 servings cooktime 1 hour ingredients 1/4 teaspoon black peppercorns 3 cloves 4 allspice berries 2 tablespoons roughly chopped sage 1 1/2 tablespoons kosher salt 6 boneless pork chops, 4 ounces each, about 1/2-inch thick 2 large apples 2 tablespoons butter All-purpose flour, for dusting 1/2 cup hard cider, plus 2 tablespoons 2 teaspoons Dijon mustard 1 1/2 cups chicken broth 2 teaspoons potato starch dissolved in 2 tablespoons cold water 3 tablespoons crème fraîche 1 tablespoon Calvados, apple brandy or Cognac, (optional) 2 tablespoons finely cut chives 2 tablespoons chopped parsley Instructions Make the spice salt: Put peppercorns, cloves, allspice and sage in a spice mill or mortar and grind to a powder.</description></item><item><title>POTATO AND WHITE BEAN PIEROGIES WITH CHEATER SAUERKRAUT</title><link>/recipes/potato-and-white-bean-pierogies-with-cheater-sauerkraut140/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/potato-and-white-bean-pierogies-with-cheater-sauerkraut140/</guid><description>POTATO AND WHITE BEAN PIEROGIES WITH CHEATER SAUERKRAUT yields 24 PIEROGIES, ENOUGH FOR 4 TO 6 PEOPLE AS A SIDE OR 10 TO 12 AS PART OF A SPREAD ingredients 2 1/2 cup all-purpose flour, plus more for kneading 1/4 tsp salt 1/4 tsp garlic powder 1 1/2 to 2 cup warm water 1 tsp olive oil 1 LB red or yellow potatoes (about 4 fist-size potatoes) 2 tsp olive oil 1/2 large yellow onion 3 cup spinach Salt yields 24 PIEROGIES, ENOUGH FOR 4 TO 6 PEOPLE AS A SIDE OR 10 TO 12 AS PART OF A SPREAD ingredients 2 1/2 cup all-purpose flour, plus more for kneading 1/4 tsp salt 1/4 tsp garlic powder 1 1/2 to 2 cup warm water 1 tsp olive oil 1 LB red or yellow potatoes (about 4 fist-size potatoes) 2 tsp olive oil 1/2 large yellow onion 3 cup spinach Salt 3 Make the filling: Chop the potatoes up into chunks no bigger than a poker chip.</description></item><item><title>POTATO LEEK CAKES</title><link>/recipes/potato-leek-cakes141/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/potato-leek-cakes141/</guid><description>POTATO LEEK CAKES yields 24 CAKES, ENOUGH FOR 6 TO 8 PEOPLE ingredients 2 1/2 cup grated potatoes (about 1 LB)* 2 1/2 cup grated potatoes (about 1 LB)i* 2 1/2 cup grated potatoes (about 1 LB)* 2 1/2 cup grated potatoes (about 1 LB)* 2 1/2 cup grated potatoes (about 1 LB)* 2 1/2 cup grated potatoes (about 1 LB)* 2 1/2 cup grated potatoes (about 1 LB) 2 TBL olive oil* 2 TBL olive oil Spray oil</description></item><item><title>POTATO LEEK SOUP</title><link>/recipes/potato-leek-soup142/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/potato-leek-soup142/</guid><description>POTATO LEEK SOUP yields 4 AS A SIDE ingredients 3 fist-size russet (baking) or yellow potatoes fist-size russet (baking) or yellow potatoes
3 medium leeks* 3 medium leeksl
3 to 4 clove garlic to 4 clove garlic
4 cup vegetable broth* 4 cup vegetable broth* 4 cup vegetable broth* 4 cup vegetable broth* 4 cup vegetable broth fresh chives or green onions</description></item><item><title>POZOLE ROJO</title><link>/recipes/pozole-rojo143/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/pozole-rojo143/</guid><description>POZOLE ROJO yields 6 HUNGRY PEOPLE, NO PROBLEM ingredients 5 large dried chiles 2 cup warm water 1 large onion 5 clove garlic 1 zucchini 2 TBL unsweetened cocoa powder 1 tsp olive oil 8 ounces tempeh 2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 1 can (29 ounces) hominy 1 TBL dried oregano 2 tsp ground cumin ¼ tsp salt 5 cup vegetable broth 1 tsp maple syrup or other liquid sweetener 2 tsp lime juice Toppings Sliced cabbage sliced green onions radishes cut into matchsticks cilantro avocado lime wedges instructions 1 Grab a big pot or griddle and toast the dried chiles on both sides until they get a little bendy and soft, about 2 minutes.</description></item><item><title>PUMPKIN CHILI</title><link>/recipes/pumpkin-chili144/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/pumpkin-chili144/</guid><description>PUMPKIN CHILI yields 4 TO 6 PEOPLE DEPENDING ON HOW MUCH THEY LIKE CHILI ingredients 1 yellow onion 1 carrot 1 bell pepper 1 tsp olive oil 2 to 3 clove garlic 1 jalapeño, minced 2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 2 ½ TBL mild chili powder 1 tsp dried oregano 1 tsp ground cumin 1 can (14.5 ounces) low-salt diced tomatoes 1 ½ cup pureed pumpkin 2 cup vegetable broth or water 3 cup cooked beans 1 TBL lime juice Toppings: cilantro, onion, jalapeños, avocado, tortilla strips Instructions 1 Chop up the onion, carrot, and bell pepper into pieces no bigger than a bean.</description></item><item><title>PUMPKIN FRENCH TOAST CASSEROLE</title><link>/recipes/pumpkin-french-toast-casserole145/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/pumpkin-french-toast-casserole145/</guid><description>PUMPKIN FRENCH TOAST CASSEROLE yields 9 X 13-INCH PAN, ENOUGH FOR 6 TO 8 PEOPLE ingredients 1 large crusty loaf of stale bread 3 TBL ground flaxseed 2 cup nondairy milk 1/2 tsp apple cider vinegar or lemon juice 1 1/2 cup canned pumpkin puree 1/4 cup packed brown sugar 1 TBL vanilla extract 2 tsp ground cinnamon 1 tsp ground ginger 1/2 tsp ground nutmeg 1/3 cup nutritional yeast Spray oil Instructions 1 Heat up the oven to 375°F.</description></item><item><title>QUESO-ISH QUESADILLAS</title><link>/recipes/quesoish-quesadillas146/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/quesoish-quesadillas146/</guid><description>QUESO-ISH QUESADILLAS yields 6 QUESADILLAS ingredients 2 tsp olive oil 1 red bell pepper 1/2 cup corn kernels 1 1/2 cup cooked pinto beans 1/4 tsp ground cumin 1 pinch salt 1 cup Butternut Squash Queso-ish Dip 2 cup shredded cabbage, red or green 6 burrito-size tortillas, whatever kind you like Instructions 0 chop bell pepper
1 In a medium skillet or sauté pan, warm up the olive oil over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>QUICK BLENDER MARINARA</title><link>/recipes/quick-blender-marinara147/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/quick-blender-marinara147/</guid><description>QUICK BLENDER MARINARA yields 5 cup ingredients 5 clove garlic 1 TBL olive oil 1 1/2 tsp dried thyme 1/2 tsp dried oregano 1 pinch of red pepper flakes 2 cans (28 ounces each) whole tomatoes 1 pinch salt Instructions 1 In a blender or food processor, throw in the garlic, olive oil, thyme, oregano, pepper flakes, and salt and pulse until that is all minced up. Grab the cans of tomatoes and drain off the extra liquid.</description></item><item><title>QUICK HOMEMADE BBQ SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/quick-homemade-bbq-sauce148/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/quick-homemade-bbq-sauce148/</guid><description>QUICK HOMEMADE BBQ SAUCE yields 5 cup ingredients 1 1/2 cup tomato sauce 1/4 cup apple cider vinegar 3 TBL brown sugar 2 TBL blackstrap molasses 1 tsp Dijon mustard 1/2 tsp liquid smoke 1/4 tsp salt Instructions In a small saucepan, mix everything together and bring that to a simmer over medium heat. Reduce to low heat and simmer for about 10 minutes, stirring every couple minutes, until it thickens up a little.</description></item><item><title>QUICK LIME AND CILANTRO SLAW</title><link>/recipes/quick-lime-and-cilantro-slaw149/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/quick-lime-and-cilantro-slaw149/</guid><description>QUICK LIME AND CILANTRO SLAW ingredients 0.5 LB of green cabbage 1 small carrot 2 TBL lime juice 2 TBL rice vinegar 1 tsp olive oil 1/8 tsp salt 1/3 cup cilantro Instructions 1 Cut the cabbage into the thinnest strips you can and make sure those pieces are no longer than
2 inches. This is a great time to get good with your knife if you are looking for a silver</description></item><item><title>QUICK PICKLED CUCUMBERS AND ONIONS</title><link>/recipes/quick-pickled-cucumbers-and-onions150/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/quick-pickled-cucumbers-and-onions150/</guid><description>QUICK PICKLED CUCUMBERS AND ONIONS yields 4 TO 6, ABOUT 2 cup ingredients 1 medium cucumber 1/4 medium red onion 1/2 tsp salt 1/2 cup rice vinegar 1 TBL apple cider vinegar Instructions 1 Cut your cucumber in half lengthwise. Skin on or off, your call. Then cut each half into a
bunch of half-moons no thicker than .25 inch. Cut the onion into wire-coat-hanger-thin strips
no longer than 2 inches.</description></item><item><title>QUINOA OATMEAL</title><link>/recipes/quinoa-oatmeal151/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/quinoa-oatmeal151/</guid><description>QUINOA OATMEAL yields 4 ingredients 4 cup water* 4 cup water* 4 cup water* 4 cup water* 4 cup watert* 4 cup water
1 pinch salt
1/2 cup almond milk
instructions 1 Heat up the water in a kettle on the stovetop or in the microwave until it is near boiling. Put the quinoa in a strainer and rinse that so it isn’t bitter after you cook it.</description></item><item><title>RED CURRY LIME SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/red-curry-lime-sauce152/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/red-curry-lime-sauce152/</guid><description>RED CURRY LIME SAUCE ingredients 1 cup vegetable broth* 1 cup vegetable brothy* 1 cup vegetable broth* 1 cup vegetable broth* 1 cup vegetable brothc* 1 cup vegetable broth* 1 cup vegetable broth* 1 cup vegetable brothu* 1 cup vegetable broth* 1 cup vegetable broth 2 tsp soy sauce or tamari* 2 tsp soy sauce or tamari* 2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 1 TBL cornstarch or arrowroot powder instructions 1 Measure out 1 TBL of the vegetable broth and set it aside in a small glass.</description></item><item><title>RED SANGRIA WITH WINTER FRUIT</title><link>/recipes/red-sangria-with-winter-fruit153/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/red-sangria-with-winter-fruit153/</guid><description>RED SANGRIA WITH WINTER FRUIT ingredients 1 bottle red wine bottle red wine
1/2 cup brandy* 1/2 cup brandy juice
2 oranges, sliced into rounds oranges, sliced into rounds* 2 oranges, sliced into rounds oranges, sliced into roundsd* 2 oranges, sliced into rounds oranges, sliced into rounds
1 apple, cut into slices apple, cut into slices
2 cup sparkling water or club soda</description></item><item><title>ROASTED BEER AND LIME CAULIFLOWER TACOS WITH CILANTRO COLESLAW</title><link>/recipes/roasted-beer-and-lime-cauliflower-tacos-with-cilantro-coleslaw154/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-beer-and-lime-cauliflower-tacos-with-cilantro-coleslaw154/</guid><description>ROASTED BEER AND LIME CAULIFLOWER TACOS WITH CILANTRO COLESLAW yields 6 TACOS ingredients 1 LB cauliflower 3/4 cup beer 1/4 cup vegetable broth 1 TBL lime juice 1 1/2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 1 1/2 TBL of your go-to chipotle hot sauce 1 to 2 clove garlic, sliced 1 1/2 tsp chili powder 1 tsp smoked paprika 1/4 tsp ground cumin 1/4 tsp garlic powder 1 pinch salt 1 TBL olive oil 0.</description></item><item><title>ROASTED BEET AND QUINOA SALAD</title><link>/recipes/roasted-beet-and-quinoa-salad155/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-beet-and-quinoa-salad155/</guid><description>ROASTED BEET AND QUINOA SALAD yields 4 AS A SIDE DRESSING ingredients 1 shallot 1 tsp Dijon mustard 3 TBL vinegar 1/4 cup olive oil 3 medium beets 1 tsp vinegar 2 tsp olive oil Salt pepper 2 cup water 1 cup quinoa, rinsed 1 cup kale 1/4 cup diced fresh herbs Instructions 0 dice shallot; peel and chop beets into small chunks (about 1.5 cup); de-stem kale and slice into strips</description></item><item><title>ROASTED BEET HUMMUS</title><link>/recipes/roasted-beet-hummus156/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-beet-hummus156/</guid><description>ROASTED BEET HUMMUS yields 3 cup, ENOUGH FOR 4 TO 6 PEOPLE ingredients 1 1/2 LB beets 1 1/2 cup chickpeas 3 clove garlic 2 TBL tahini 2 TBL olive oil 2 TBL lemon juice 2 TBL orange juice 1/2 tsp salt WALNUT-HERB CRUMBLE 1/4 cup walnuts, toasted 3 TBL minced fresh dill 3 TBL minced green onions 1 pinch salt Instructions peel, roast, and chop beets 1 In a food processor or blender, combine the beets, chickpeas, garlic, tahini, olive oil, citrus juices, and salt.</description></item><item><title>ROASTED BROCCOLI AND MILLET PILAF</title><link>/recipes/roasted-broccoli-and-millet-pilaf157/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-broccoli-and-millet-pilaf157/</guid><description>ROASTED BROCCOLI AND MILLET PILAF yields 4 AS A SIDE ingredients 1 crown broccoli 1 tsp plus 1 TBL olive oil 1 cup uncooked millet 2 cup water Salt pepper 5 clove roasted garlic 1 TBL lemon juice Instructions 1 Crank your oven to 400°F. Grab a rimmed baking sheet.
2 Cut the broccoli into chunks no bigger than your thumb. Toss the broccoli with 1 tsp
of the oil, pour it in one layer on the baking sheet, and roast the broccoli until it looks a little</description></item><item><title>ROASTED CARROT AND CUMIN DRESSING</title><link>/recipes/roasted-carrot-and-cumin-dressing158/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-carrot-and-cumin-dressing158/</guid><description>ROASTED CARROT AND CUMIN DRESSING ingredients 3 medium carrots* 3 medium carrotsl* 3 medium carrots* 3 medium carrots* 3 medium carrots* 3 medium carrots* 3 medium carrots* 3 medium carrots
2 TBL orange juice* 2 TBL orange juicel
instructions 1 Heat up your oven to 375°F. Chop up your carrots into chunks no bigger than .5 inch. Toss them together with the oil, cumin, and salt.</description></item><item><title>ROASTED CAULIFLOWER AND MUSHROOM BANH MI</title><link>/recipes/roasted-cauliflower-and-mushroom-banh-mi159/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-cauliflower-and-mushroom-banh-mi159/</guid><description>ROASTED CAULIFLOWER AND MUSHROOM BANH MI yields 6 FULL-SIZE SANDWICHES OR 12 HALF SANDWICHES BECAUSE, YOU KNOW, MATH ingredients 2 TBL soy sauce or tamari 3 TBL rice vinegar 1 TBL lime juice 1 TBL neutral oil, such as grapeseed 2 tsp brown sugar 1 tsp S title: &amp;ldquo;ROASTED CAULIFLOWER AND MUSHROOM BANH MI&amp;rdquo; tags:
recipe ROASTED CAULIFLOWER AND MUSHROOM BANH MI yields 6 FULL-SIZE SANDWICHES OR 12 HALF SANDWICHES BECAUSE, YOU KNOW, MATH ingredients 2 TBL soy sauce or tamari 3 TBL rice vinegar 1 TBL lime juice 1 TBL neutral oil, such as grapeseed 2 tsp brown sugar 1 tsp Ss&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Optional toppers: cilantro, mint, cucumber rounds, jalapeño slices Instructions 0 cut radishes and carrots into matchsticks.</description></item><item><title>ROASTED CHICKPEA AND BROCCOLI BURRITOS</title><link>/recipes/roasted-chickpea-and-broccoli-burritos160/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-chickpea-and-broccoli-burritos160/</guid><description>ROASTED CHICKPEA AND BROCCOLI BURRITOS yields 4 TO 6 BURRITOS ingredients 1 large yellow onion 1 red bell pepper 1 large crown of broccoli 3 cup cooked chickpeas 3 TBL olive oil 1-2 TBL soy sauce 2 tsp chili powder 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp smoked paprika 1/2 tsp ground coriander Cayenne pepper, to taste 4 clove garlic 0.5 lime 4-6 flour tortillas Burrito trimmings such as spinach, avocado, cilantro, and Fire-Roasted Salsa Instructions 1 Crank your oven to 425°F.</description></item><item><title>ROASTED GARLIC DIP</title><link>/recipes/roasted-garlic-dip161/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-garlic-dip161/</guid><description>ROASTED GARLIC DIP yields 5 cup ingredients 12 ounces soft silken tofu 5 clove roasted garlic 2 TBL minced shallot or white onion 1 TBL apple cider vinegar or lemon juice 1 TBL minced chives 1 TBL minced fresh parsley 1/2 tsp salt Instructions 1 Throw the tofu, garlic, and shallot into a blender or food processor and run until it looks all smooth. If you put the papery garlic skin in there too, we swear we’re going drive over there and confiscate your whole kitchen from you.</description></item><item><title>ROASTED GARLIC PULL-APART BREAD</title><link>/recipes/roasted-garlic-pullapart-bread162/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-garlic-pullapart-bread162/</guid><description>ROASTED GARLIC PULL-APART BREAD yields 6 TO 8 PEOPLE ingredients 2 bulbs garlic, roasted bulbs garlic, roasted
1 clove raw garlic* 1 clove raw garlico* 1 clove raw garlic* 1 clove raw garlic* 1 clove raw garlici* 1 clove raw garlic* 1 clove raw garlic* 1 clove raw garlic* 1 clove raw garlic
1 loaf crusty French bread
2 tsp nutritional yeast* 2 tsp nutritional yeastparsley</description></item><item><title>ROASTED GARLIC WHITE SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/roasted-garlic-white-sauce163/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-garlic-white-sauce163/</guid><description>ROASTED GARLIC WHITE SAUCE yields 25 cup ingredients 3 TBL whole wheat pastry or all-purpose flour* 3 TBL whole wheat pastry or all-purpose flourl* 3 TBL whole wheat pastry or all-purpose flour
1 1/2 cup unsweetened nondairy milk
2 bulbs garlic, roasted bulbs garlic, roasted
2 TBL nutritional yeast* 2 TBL nutritional yeasti* 2 TBL nutritional yeast
1/4 tsp salt</description></item><item><title>ROASTED POTATO SALAD WITH FRESH HERBS</title><link>/recipes/roasted-potato-salad-with-fresh-herbs164/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-potato-salad-with-fresh-herbs164/</guid><description>ROASTED POTATO SALAD WITH FRESH HERBS yields 4 AS A SIDE ingredients small white or yellow potatoes, unpeeled 1 TBL olive oil 1/2 tsp smoked paprika (optional) 1/4 tsp salt 1/2 cup diced fresh parsley 1/2 cup sliced green onions 1 clove garlic 2 TBL olive oil 2 TBL red wine vinegar 1 TBL water 1 tsp lemon juice Instructions 1 Crank your oven to 400°F.
2 Slice the potatoes in half lengthwise.</description></item><item><title>ROASTED POTATOES WITH RED PEPPER DIPPING SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/roasted-potatoes-with-red-pepper-dipping-sauce165/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-potatoes-with-red-pepper-dipping-sauce165/</guid><description>ROASTED POTATOES WITH RED PEPPER DIPPING SAUCE yields 4 PEOPLE, BUT YOU CAN DOUBLE OR TRIPLE, NO PROBLEM ingredients small yellow or red potatoes, sliced in half 2 tsp olive oil 1 TBL cornmeal 1/2 tsp smoked paprika 1 pinch salt 1/4 cup chives or green onions 2 roasted red bell peppers 1/4 cup sliced almonds, raw or toasted 2 TBL vegetable broth or water 1 TBL tomato paste 1 TBL sherry vinegar or red wine vinegar 1 clove garlic 2 tsp olive oil 1/2 tsp smoked paprika 1/4 tsp salt Instructions 1 Crank your oven to 425°F.</description></item><item><title>ROASTED SRIRACHA CAULIFLOWER BITES WITH PEANUT DIPPING SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/roasted-sriracha-cauliflower-bites-with-peanut-dipping-sauce166/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-sriracha-cauliflower-bites-with-peanut-dipping-sauce166/</guid><description>ROASTED SRIRACHA CAULIFLOWER BITES WITH PEANUT DIPPING SAUCE yields 4 TO 6 PEOPLE, OR 1 PERSON WITH NO FEARS ingredients 2 LB cauliflower 1/2 cup flour 1/2 cup water 2 tsp oil 0.5 to 2⁄3 cup Sriracha or similar-style hot sauce 1/4 cup rice vinegar 1/2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 1/4 cup warm water 1/4 cup plus 2 TBL creamy peanut butter 2 TBL rice vinegar 2 TBL lime juice 2 tsp minced fresh ginger 1 tsp soy sauce or tamari 1 tsp maple syrup or agave syrup 1 cucumber, cut into finger-long sticks Instructions 1 Crank your oven to 450°F.</description></item><item><title>ROASTED WINTER SQUASH WITH MINT</title><link>/recipes/roasted-winter-squash-with-mint167/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/roasted-winter-squash-with-mint167/</guid><description>ROASTED WINTER SQUASH WITH MINT yields 6 TO 8 PEOPLE AS A SIDE ingredients 2 TBL olive oil* 2 TBL olive oil * 2 TBL olive oil 1/2 tsp salt 0.5 yellow onion, cut into thin strips
2 LB winter squash* 2 LB winter squashice
1 green onion green onion
1 TBL mint* 1 TBL mint
Black pepper
instructions finely chop green onion (about 2 TBL); chop mint 0 seed squash and cut into 1-inch-thick wedges or rings, but with the skin on for looks.</description></item><item><title>ROOT VEGGIE FRIES</title><link>/recipes/root-veggie-fries168/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/root-veggie-fries168/</guid><description>ROOT VEGGIE FRIES ingredients 5 TBL brown rice flour or white flour* 5 TBL brown rice flour or white flour * 5 TBL brown rice flour or white flour* 5 TBL brown rice flour or white flour* 5 TBL brown rice flour or white flour* 5 TBL brown rice flour or white flour* 5 TBL brown rice flour or white flour* 5 TBL brown rice flour or white floure or tamari</description></item><item><title>ROSEMARY CARAMEL CORN</title><link>/recipes/rosemary-caramel-corn169/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/rosemary-caramel-corn169/</guid><description>ROSEMARY CARAMEL CORN yields 6 TO 8 PEOPLE TO MUNCH ON ingredients 8 cup unseasoned popped popcorn 1/4 cup butter 1 TBL loosely packed chopped fresh rosemary 1/3 cup packed brown sugar 1/4 cup maple syrup 1/2 tsp salt 1/2 tsp baking soda Instructions 1 Warm up your oven to 250°F. Line a rimmed baking sheet with parchment paper.
2 Pour the popcorn in one big bowl with tall sides or two medium bowls so that you don’t spill it later while you’re trying to mix.</description></item><item><title>SALSA VERDE</title><link>/recipes/salsa-verde170/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/salsa-verde170/</guid><description>SALSA VERDE yields 4 TO 6, ABOUT 2.5 cup ingredients 1 1/2 LB s tomatillos 2 jalapeños jalapeños 0.5 white onion 2 clove garlic* 2 clove garlicr* 2 clove garlic* 2 clove garlic 1/8 tsp salt instructions 0 chop onion 1 Turn on the broiler in your oven and get it nice and hot. 2 Tear off all that loose, papery skin on the tomatillos and wash away all that sticky left on the fruit.</description></item><item><title>SAVORY GRITS</title><link>/recipes/savory-grits171/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/savory-grits171/</guid><description>SAVORY GRITS yields 6 cup ingredients 3 1/2 cup vegetable broth or water* 3 1/2 cup vegetable broth or watern* 3 1/2 cup vegetable broth or water* 3 1/2 cup vegetable broth or water* 3 1/2 cup vegetable broth or water
1/4 cup nutritional yeast
instructions 1 Grab a large pot and bring the broth and milk to a boil over medium heat. Gently whisk in the grits and the salt.</description></item><item><title>SAVORY GRITS WITH MIDSUMMER SUCCOTASH</title><link>/recipes/savory-grits-with-midsummer-succotash172/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/savory-grits-with-midsummer-succotash172/</guid><description>SAVORY GRITS WITH MIDSUMMER SUCCOTASH yields 4 DAYS AND LEAVE THE OTHER LAZY S TO FEND FOR THEMSELVES ingredients 2 tsp olive oil* 2 tsp olive oil or white onion
1 zucchini zucchini* 1 zucchini zucchiniper red bell pepper
1 clove garlic* 1 clove garlice* 1 clove garlic* 1 clove garlic* 1 clove garlicb* 1 clove garlic
1 tsp lemon juice
1/4 tsp salt Toppers: chopped chives, fresh basil, dill</description></item><item><title>SAVORY MINI WAFFLES</title><link>/recipes/savory-mini-waffles173/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/savory-mini-waffles173/</guid><description>SAVORY MINI WAFFLES yields 12 MINI WAFFLES, DEPENDING ON HOW YOU POUR THAT ingredients 2 1/4 cup unsweetened nondairy milk (your favorite) 1 tsp apple cider vinegar or lemon juice 1 1/2 cup finely ground cornmeal 1 cup all-purpose or whole wheat flour 2 TBL nutritional yeast 1 TBL baking powder 1/2 tsp salt Smoky onions (from Cobb Salad) 2 TBL olive oil 2 TBL minced chives or green onions Spray oil Roasted Garlic Dip Instructions 1 Warm up the waffle iron.</description></item><item><title>SAVORY TEMPEH AND CARROT SANDWICHES</title><link>/recipes/savory-tempeh-and-carrot-sandwiches174/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/savory-tempeh-and-carrot-sandwiches174/</guid><description>SAVORY TEMPEH AND CARROT SANDWICHES yields 4 REGULAR-SIZE SANDWICHES ingredients 8 ounces tempeh 2 medium carrots 1 cup vegetable broth or water 1/4 cup soy sauce or tamari 2 TBL lemon juice 1 1/2 TBL liquid smoke 2 tsp maple syrup or other syrupy sweetener 4 clove garlic, cut into thick slices 1/2 tsp ground cumin 1 TBL olive oil Lettuce, sliced tomato, avocado, red onion, and mustard 4 rolls or 8 slices of bread, toasted Instructions 1 Slice the tempeh into planks about .</description></item><item><title>SAVORY TOMATO AND NECTARINE COBBLER</title><link>/recipes/savory-tomato-and-nectarine-cobbler175/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/savory-tomato-and-nectarine-cobbler175/</guid><description>SAVORY TOMATO AND NECTARINE COBBLER yields 6 TO 8 PEOPLE ingredients 1 LB nectarines (about 3 fist-size ones)* 1 LB nectarines (about 3 fist-size ones) * 1 LB nectarines (about 3 fist-size ones)* 1 LB nectarines (about 3 fist-size ones)
2 tsp olive oil 0.5 yellow onion, cut into thin strips
3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlicb* 3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlicc* 3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlic* 3 clove garlica* 3 clove garlic</description></item><item><title>SCRAMBLED CURRY TOFU FRIED RICE</title><link>/recipes/scrambled-curry-tofu-fried-rice176/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/scrambled-curry-tofu-fried-rice176/</guid><description>SCRAMBLED CURRY TOFU FRIED RICE yields 4 TO 6 HUNGRY SONS OF ingredients 1 tsp refined coconut or olive oil 2 carrots carrots* 2 carrots carrotsper red bell pepper 0.5 yellow onion
3 cup spinach* 3 cup spinacha* 3 cup spinach
2 tsp refined coconut or olive oil
16 ounces extra-firm tofu ounces extra-firm tofu
1 tsp soy sauce or tamari* 1 tsp soy sauce or tamariu* 1 tsp soy sauce or tamari* 1 tsp soy sauce or tamari* 1 tsp soy sauce or tamarii* 1 tsp soy sauce or tamari* 1 tsp soy sauce or tamari* 1 tsp soy sauce or tamari cooked short-grain brown rice</description></item><item><title>SHAVED ASPARAGUS PIZZA</title><link>/recipes/shaved-asparagus-pizza177/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/shaved-asparagus-pizza177/</guid><description>SHAVED ASPARAGUS PIZZA yields 2 INDIVIDUAL PIZZAS ingredients 1 LB asparagus 1 TBL lemon juice 1 tsp olive oil 1 pinch salt Olive oil, for brushing the crust Toppings: arugula, chives, lemon juice, Hot sauce Instructions 0 chop toppings
1 Make the pizza dough through step 4. While that yeasty beast is rising, make the garlic sauce and start the oven cranking to 475°F. Cook this on a chilly day and give your heater a break.</description></item><item><title>SHREDDED CARROT AND APPLE MUFFINS</title><link>/recipes/shredded-carrot-and-apple-muffins178/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/shredded-carrot-and-apple-muffins178/</guid><description>SHREDDED CARROT AND APPLE MUFFINS yields 12 STANDARD MUFFINS Ingredients lemon juice 1 tsp vanilla extract 1/2 cup nuts like walnuts or almonds (optional as ) Instructions 1 Heat your oven to 375°F. Grab a muffin tin and grease that er up or throw in some
muffin liners.
2 In a big bowl, whisk together the flour, sugar, baking powder, cinnamon, and salt. In a
smaller bowl, stir together the almond milk, carrots, apple, oil, lemon juice, and vanilla until</description></item><item><title>SILKY ROASTED BELL PEPPER PASTA WITH ZUCCHINI AND BASIL RIBBONS</title><link>/recipes/silky-roasted-bell-pepper-pasta-with-zucchini-and-basil-ribbons179/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/silky-roasted-bell-pepper-pasta-with-zucchini-and-basil-ribbons179/</guid><description>SILKY ROASTED BELL PEPPER PASTA WITH ZUCCHINI AND BASIL RIBBONS yields 4 AS A MAIN DISH, BUT IF YOU’RE SOLO THESE ingredients 12 ounces soft silken tofu 2 roasted red bell peppers 3 to 4 clove garlic 1 1/2 TBL red wine vinegar 2 tsp olive oil 1/4 cup nutritional yeast 3/4 tsp salt 1 tsp red pepper flakes 1 LB spaghetti, linguine, or fettuccine 4 medium zucchini 1 cup basil, sliced into thin strips Instructions 0 chop roasted bell peppers</description></item><item><title>SMOKED ALMOND AND CHICKPEA SALAD SAMMIES</title><link>/recipes/smoked-almond-and-chickpea-salad-sammies180/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/smoked-almond-and-chickpea-salad-sammies180/</guid><description>SMOKED ALMOND AND CHICKPEA SALAD SAMMIES yields 4 TO 6 SANDWICHES ingredients 2 1/2 tsp liquid smoke* 2 1/2 tsp liquid smokeo* 2 1/2 tsp liquid smoke* 2 1/2 tsp liquid smoke* 2 1/2 tsp liquid smoker* 2 1/2 tsp liquid smoke* 2 1/2 tsp liquid smoke* 2 1/2 tsp liquid smokea* 2 1/2 tsp liquid smoke
1 tsp garlic powder
3/4 cup raw almonds* 3/4 cup raw almondsh* 3/4 cup raw almonds</description></item><item><title>SMOKY BLACK-EYED PEAS WITH ROASTED SWEET POTATOES AND COLLARDS</title><link>/recipes/smoky-blackeyed-peas-with-roasted-sweet-potatoes-and-collards181/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/smoky-blackeyed-peas-with-roasted-sweet-potatoes-and-collards181/</guid><description>SMOKY BLACK-EYED PEAS WITH ROASTED SWEET POTATOES AND COLLARDS yields 6 ingredients 1 1/2 cup dried black-eyed peas 6 medium to large sweet potatoes 2 tsp olive oil 1 onion 3 ribs celery 1/4 tsp salt 1/2 tsp ground allspice 1/2 tsp ground nutmeg 1/2 tsp paprika 2 to 3 clove garlic 3 to 4 chipotle peppers in adobo sauce 3 cup vegetable broth 2 or 3 batches Wilted Greens Instructions 0 chop onion, celery, chipole peppers.</description></item><item><title>SMOKY MAPLE MARINADE</title><link>/recipes/smoky-maple-marinade182/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/smoky-maple-marinade182/</guid><description>SMOKY MAPLE MARINADE ingredients 2 TBL maple syrup 1 TBL liquid smoke 1 TBL lemon juice 1 TBL tomato paste 1 TBL olive oil 2 clove garlic, thickly sliced Instructions 1 Combine all ingredients</description></item><item><title>SOCAL GOURMET CARROT DOGS</title><link>/recipes/socal-gourmet-carrot-dogs183/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/socal-gourmet-carrot-dogs183/</guid><description>SOCAL GOURMET CARROT DOGS yields 8 DOGS ingredients 8 hotdog buns, whatever you like hotdog buns, whatever you like* 8 hotdog buns, whatever you like hotdog buns, whatever you likei* 8 hotdog buns, whatever you like hotdog buns, whatever you like 3 jalapeños, sliced into thin rounds jalapeños, sliced into thin rounds Your favorite pico de gallo–style salsa
instructions 1 Make the carrot dogs and pesto. 2 To assemble a dog, smear some pesto on the inside of a bun, lay down a couple slices of avocado and jalapeño, and top the damn thing off with some salsa.</description></item><item><title>SOURDOUGH FRENCH TOAST</title><link>/recipes/sourdough-french-toast184/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/sourdough-french-toast184/</guid><description>SOURDOUGH FRENCH TOAST Instructions 1 In a pie pan or similar shallow dish, mix together the ground chia seeds and flour. Slowly
whisk in the milk so that doesn’t get all lumpy. SLOWLY, MOTHER ER. Now
let that sit for 15 minutes. Make your sleepy ass some coffee and then cut the bread up into 1-
inch-thick slices while you wait.
2 Whisk the batter after about 15 minutes and then slowly add the nutritional yeast and stir.</description></item><item><title>SPARKLING WINTER CITRUS AND GIN PUNCH</title><link>/recipes/sparkling-winter-citrus-and-gin-punch185/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/sparkling-winter-citrus-and-gin-punch185/</guid><description>SPARKLING WINTER CITRUS AND GIN PUNCH yields 9 cup ingredients 2 bottles (750ml each) champagne or sparkling wine 1 cup fresh grapefruit juice ½ cup fresh blood orange or navel orange juice 1 ¼ cup gin 1 cup sparkling water ¼ cup agave syrup or other syrupy sweetener Ice Grapefruit slices, orange slices, and sprigs of mint or rosemary, for the punch bowl instructions 1 Chill everything for a couple of hours before throwing the punch together.</description></item><item><title>SPICED CHICKPEA WRAPS WITH TAHINI DRESSING</title><link>/recipes/spiced-chickpea-wraps-with-tahini-dressing186/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/spiced-chickpea-wraps-with-tahini-dressing186/</guid><description>SPICED CHICKPEA WRAPS WITH TAHINI DRESSING yields 4 BIG WRAPS ingredients 3 TBL warm water 1 ½ TBL lemon juice 1 TBL rice vinegar 1 TBL olive oil 1 tsp soy sauce or tamari 2 clove garlic 1 TBL olive oil 3 cup cooked chickpeas 2 TBL lemon juice 1 tsp maple syrup 1 tsp soy sauce or tamari 2 tsp smoked paprika 2 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp garlic powder ¼-½ tsp cayenne pepper 4 large tortillas Spinach Cucumber sticks Carrot sticks instructions 1 To make the dressing, mix all that together in a small glass until it is smooth and creamy.</description></item><item><title>SPICY PICKLED CARROTS</title><link>/recipes/spicy-pickled-carrots187/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/spicy-pickled-carrots187/</guid><description>SPICY PICKLED CARROTS yields 4 TO 6, OR ONE LARGE JAR ingredients 2 jalapeños jalapeños
3/4 cup distilled white vinegar* 3/4 cup distilled white vinegarc* 3/4 cup distilled white vinegar
1 tsp dried oregano
1 bay leaf bay leaf
1/2 tsp cumin seeds* 1/2 tsp cumin seeds * 1/2 tsp cumin seeds* 1/2 tsp cumin seeds* 1/2 tsp cumin seeds, smashed</description></item><item><title>SPIKED CITRUS ICED TEA</title><link>/recipes/spiked-citrus-iced-tea188/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/spiked-citrus-iced-tea188/</guid><description>SPIKED CITRUS ICED TEA yields 8 PEOPLE ingredients 1 gallon water 8 black tea bags 1/4-1/2 cup maple syrup 2 1/2 cup whiskey 1/2 cup orange juice 1/3 cup lemon juice Ice Orange and lemon slices, for garnish Instructions 1 In a large pot, heat the water over medium-high heat until you see bubbles forming on the bottom. You don’t need to boil it. Turn off the heat and add the tea bags.</description></item><item><title>SPRING VEGGIE BOWL WITH RED CURRY LIME SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/spring-veggie-bowl-with-red-curry-lime-sauce189/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/spring-veggie-bowl-with-red-curry-lime-sauce189/</guid><description>SPRING VEGGIE BOWL WITH RED CURRY LIME SAUCE yields 4 TO 6 BOWLS ingredients Instructions 1 Cook the noodles according to the package directions. When they’re all done, drain them,
run them under cool water for a sec, and then set them aside. We will need these ers later.
2 Next, make the Red Curry Lime Sauce.
3 Brush the baby bok choy with 1 TBL of the oil and toss the asparagus with the other</description></item><item><title>SRIRACHA AIOLI</title><link>/recipes/sriracha-aioli190/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/sriracha-aioli190/</guid><description>SRIRACHA AIOLI ingredients 2 TBL Sriracha or similar style hot sauce 1 TBL lemon juice 1 tsp Dijon mustard 2 clove garlic 1/8 tsp salt Instructions 1 Throw everything together in a blender or food processor and run it until everything looks smooth and mixed up, about 1 minute. This flavorful mother er will keep in the fridge for about 2 weeks. If it starts to separate, just throw it back in the blender and emulsify its ass one more time.</description></item><item><title>STOVETOP HERB POPCORN</title><link>/recipes/stovetop-herb-popcorn191/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/stovetop-herb-popcorn191/</guid><description>STOVETOP HERB POPCORN yields 4 TO 6, ABOUT 8 cup ingredients 2 tsp nutritional yeast* 2 tsp nutritional yeasts* 2 tsp nutritional yeast* 2 tsp nutritional yeast* 2 tsp nutritional yeasto* 2 tsp nutritional yeast* 2 tsp nutritional yeast* 2 tsp nutritional yeasteseed oil
1/2 cup dried corn kernels* 1/2 cup dried corn kernelse oil
optional *
1/8 tsp salt
instructions 1 Make the herb topping.</description></item><item><title>STRAWBERRY SHORTCAKE</title><link>/recipes/strawberry-shortcake192/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/strawberry-shortcake192/</guid><description>STRAWBERRY SHORTCAKE yields 8 ingredients 1 LB strawberries* 1 LB strawberries* 1 LB strawberries* 1 LB strawberries* 1 LB strawberrieso* 1 LB strawberries* 1 LB strawberries* 1 LB strawberries* 1 LB strawberries
1/2 tsp salt
1 cup canned coconut milk* 1 cup canned coconut milka extract
Whipped Cream
instructions 1 Make the filling: Chop the strawberries up into pieces the size of a button and throw them in a bowl.</description></item><item><title>STRAWBERRY-CUCUMBER SMASH</title><link>/recipes/strawberrycucumber-smash193/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/strawberrycucumber-smash193/</guid><description>STRAWBERRY-CUCUMBER SMASH ingredients 6 slices (.25 inch thick) cucumber 12 fresh mint leaves (optional) 1/2 cup gin 1-2 tsp of your favorite liquid sweetener like agave syrup Ice 1/2 cup tonic or sparkling water Instructions 1 Grab a big-ass jar with a tight-fitting lid. Throw in the strawberries, cucumber, mint (if you’re using it), gin, 1 tsp agave, and a big handful of ice.
2 Shake the ever-living out of it until the gin looks all pink and lovely and the mint is beat to .</description></item><item><title>STUFFED MUSHROOMS</title><link>/recipes/stuffed-mushrooms194/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/stuffed-mushrooms194/</guid><description>STUFFED MUSHROOMS yields 6 TO 8 PEOPLE ingredients 25 large button or cremini mushrooms 2 tsp olive oil 1/2 medium yellow or white onion 1/2 cup cooked millet or quinoa 2 clove garlic 2 green onions, finely chopped (about .25 cup) 1/4 cup fresh dill or parsley 1/2 tsp grated lemon zest 1/2 tsp salt 1/4 tsp black pepper Spray oil Instructions 1 Crank your oven to 375°F. Set aside a rimmed baking sheet.</description></item><item><title>SUMMER NIGHT PAELLA</title><link>/recipes/summer-night-paella195/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/summer-night-paella195/</guid><description>SUMMER NIGHT PAELLA yields 4 TO 6 PEOPLE ingredients 2 1/2 cup vegetable broth 3/4 cup dry white wine 1 pinch of saffron threads 1 TBL olive oil 1/2 medium yellow onion 3/4 cup button or cremini mushrooms 2 large tomatoes 1/4 tsp salt 1 cup frozen lima beans 3 clove garlic 1 1/2 tsp smoked paprika 1 1/2 cup short- or medium-grain white rice 4 spears asparagus, halved lengthwise 1 red bell pepper, roasted, cut into strips 1 can (14 ounces) water-packed artichoke hearts, drained, rinsed, and quartered 2 TBL lemon juice Paprika, for garnish Instructions 0 chop onion and tomatoes</description></item><item><title>SUMMER SQUASH SOUP</title><link>/recipes/summer-squash-soup196/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/summer-squash-soup196/</guid><description>SUMMER SQUASH SOUP ingredients 1 1/2 TBL olive oil 0.5 onion 2 ribs celery 1 carrot, sliced into thin half-moons 1 russet potato 3 large yellow squash, sliced into half-moons .125 inch thick 3 clove garlic 1/2 tsp salt 4 cup vegetable broth 1/3 cup sliced chives or green onions Instructions 0 chop onion, celery, potato into dice-size cubes
1 In a large soup pot, heat the oil over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>SWEET CITRUS MARINADE</title><link>/recipes/sweet-citrus-marinade197/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/sweet-citrus-marinade197/</guid><description>SWEET CITRUS MARINADE ingredients 1 TBL brown sugar 1 TBL minced fresh ginger 1 TBL olive oil 2 tsp Sriracha or similar hot sauce 2 clove garlic, thickly sliced Instructions 1 Combine all ingredients</description></item><item><title>SWEET CORN AND BLACK-EYED PEA DIP</title><link>/recipes/sweet-corn-and-blackeyed-pea-dip198/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/sweet-corn-and-blackeyed-pea-dip198/</guid><description>SWEET CORN AND BLACK-EYED PEA DIP yields 4 TO 6, ABOUT 5 cup ingredients 1 red bell pepper 1 small tomato 3 cup cooked black-eyed peas 1 cup raw corn kernels 1/2 cup sliced green onions 1/3 cup cilantro 2 clove garlic 1 jalapeño, minced 2 TBL olive oil 2 TBL lime juice 2 TBL red wine vinegar 1/4 tsp ground cumin 1/4 tsp salt Instructions 1 Chop up the bell pepper and tomato into pieces about the size of a bean.</description></item><item><title>SWEET CORN AND GREEN CHILE BAKED FLAUTAS</title><link>/recipes/sweet-corn-and-green-chile-baked-flautas199/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/sweet-corn-and-green-chile-baked-flautas199/</guid><description>SWEET CORN AND GREEN CHILE BAKED FLAUTAS yields 12 FLAUTAS ingredients 1 tsp olive oil* 1 tsp olive oilr* 1 tsp olive oil* 1 tsp olive oil* 1 tsp olive oil cumin
1/2 tsp salt* 1/2 tsp saltarlic to 5 clove garlic
3 cup cooked pinto beans
1 can (4 ounces) mild green chiles can (4 ounces) mild green chiles
1 tsp lime juice* 1 tsp lime juicern kernels</description></item><item><title>SWEET FRESH HERB SALSA</title><link>/recipes/sweet-fresh-herb-salsa200/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/sweet-fresh-herb-salsa200/</guid><description>SWEET FRESH HERB SALSA yields 75 CUP ingredients 1 cup torn basil leaves 1/2 cup cilantro 1/2 cup sliced green onions 1 jalapeño, minced 1 clove garlic 3 TBL rice vinegar 1 TBL orange juice 1 TBL lime juice 1 TBL olive oil Instructions 1 Throw everything together in a food processor and let run until everything is minced up.
No food processor?
Just mince everything up extra tiny by hand and mix that in a cup.</description></item><item><title>SWEET POTATO, SQUASH, AND BLACK BEAN ENCHILADAS</title><link>/recipes/sweet-potato-squash-and-black-bean-enchiladas201/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/sweet-potato-squash-and-black-bean-enchiladas201/</guid><description>SWEET POTATO, SQUASH, AND BLACK BEAN ENCHILADAS yields 8 ENCHILADAS ingredients 2 ¼ cup vegetable broth 1/3 cup tomato paste 2 ½ TBL chili powder 2 tsp ground cumin 1 ½ tsp dried oregano 2 to 3 clove garlic 2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 1 TBL lime juice 1 large sweet potato 2 tsp olive oil 0.5 yellow onion 1 medium yellow squash 1 tsp chili powder ½ tsp ground cumin ½ tsp salt 2 clove garlic 1 ½ cup cooked black beans 1 tsp maple syrup or agave syrup 1 pack tortillas Sliced avocado fresh cilantro instructions 0 chop onion and potato into nickel-size pieces; grate squash (about 1 cup) 1 Make the enchilada sauce: Dump everything but the lime juice into a medium saucepan and bring to a simmer.</description></item><item><title>SWEET SESAME TERIYAKI-STYLE SAUCE</title><link>/recipes/sweet-sesame-teriyakistyle-sauce202/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/sweet-sesame-teriyakistyle-sauce202/</guid><description>SWEET SESAME TERIYAKI-STYLE SAUCE yields 1 CUP ingredients 2 TBL rice vinegar* 2 TBL rice vinegarf* 2 TBL rice vinegar* 2 TBL rice vinegar* 2 TBL rice vinegarr* 2 TBL rice vinegar* 2 TBL rice vinegar
2 tsp cornstarch or arrowroot powder* 2 tsp cornstarch or arrowroot powder
optional *
2 TBL sesame seeds
instructions 1 In a small saucepan, mix together the soy sauce or tamari, broth, orange juice, vinegar, sweetener, sesame oil, ginger, and garlic and stir over medium-low heat.</description></item><item><title>TAHINI DRESSING</title><link>/recipes/tahini-dressing203/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/tahini-dressing203/</guid><description>TAHINI DRESSING ingredients 1 TBL citrus juice 1/2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 2 TBL toasted sesame oil 3 TBL olive oil Instructions Pour all the ingredients into a jar and shake that up. Taste and add more of
whateverthe you think it needs. Orange, lime, or lemon works best.</description></item><item><title>TEMPEH AND SPINACH CALZONES WITH ALMOND RICOTTA</title><link>/recipes/tempeh-and-spinach-calzones-with-almond-ricotta204/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/tempeh-and-spinach-calzones-with-almond-ricotta204/</guid><description>TEMPEH AND SPINACH CALZONES WITH ALMOND RICOTTA yields 8 HAND-SIZE CALZONES ingredients 2 tsp olive oil 8 ounces tempeh 1 yellow onion 1 TBL soy sauce 2 tsp fennel seeds 1 tsp dried basil 1 tsp dried oregano 1 tsp dried thyme 6 cup spinach 1 TBL lemon juice 3 clove garlic Red pepper flakes 1/3 cup sliced almonds, toasted 14 ounces extra-firm tofu, drained 2 clove garlic 1 TBL olive oil 1 TBL lemon juice ½ tsp salt 1/3 cup nutritional yeast Spray oil Quick Blender Marinara or Blender Red Sauce, for dipping instructions 0 chop onion 1 Make the dough according to the directions because we’re not about to type that out again.</description></item><item><title>TEMPEH PEANUT NOODLES WITH</title><link>/recipes/tempeh-peanut-noodles-with205/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/tempeh-peanut-noodles-with205/</guid><description>TEMPEH PEANUT NOODLES WITH yields 4 ingredients 2 tsp toasted sesame oil 2 tsp lime juice 2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 1 tsp maple syrup or agave syrup 1 tsp chili-garlic paste or Asian-style hot sauce (optional) 12 ounces noodles 6 cup kale, sliced into bite-size pieces 1 tsp grapeseed oil 8 ounces tempeh 1 tsp soy sauce or tamari 1 TBL rice vinegar 2 TBL minced fresh ginger 3 clove garlic 1/2 cup sliced green onions Instructions 1 First make the peanut sauce.</description></item><item><title>TEX-MEX ENCHILADAS</title><link>/recipes/texmex-enchiladas206/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/texmex-enchiladas206/</guid><description>TEX-MEX ENCHILADAS yields 8 ENCHILADAS, ENOUGH FOR 4 TO 6 PEOPLE ingredients 2 tsp olive oil 1 yellow onion, finely chopped 1 small green bell pepper, finely chopped 2 jalapeños, seeded and finely chopped 1 clove garlic 2 tsp ground cumin 1/4 tsp salt 1 1/2 cup vegetable broth 1 can (15 ounces) tomato sauce 1/4 cup cilantro 1 TBL lime juice 0.5 yellow onion 2 clove garlic 3 cup cooked pinto beans 1/4 tsp ground cumin 1/4 tsp salt 2 cup fresh or frozen corn kernels 2 avocados 2 tsp lime juice 8 tortillas Instructions 1 Make the ranchero sauce: In a medium saucepan, warm up the oil over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>TLTA SAMMIES</title><link>/recipes/tlta-sammies207/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/tlta-sammies207/</guid><description>TLTA SAMMIES yields 4 SAMMIES ON REGULAR-SIZE LOAF BREAD ingredients 8 ounces tempeh BACON-ISH MARINADE 1 1/2 cup vegetable broth 1/4 cup soy sauce or tamari 2 TBL apple cider vinegar 2 TBL liquid smoke 1 TBL blackstrap molasses 1 tsp smoked paprika 1 tsp onion powder 3 clove garlic, sliced 1 TBL olive oil Lettuce Sliced tomatoes, avocado, and red onion 8 slices bread, like sourdough, toasted Dijon mustard Instructions 1 Slice the tempeh into planks about .</description></item><item><title>TO-GO BREAKFAST BARS</title><link>/recipes/togo-breakfast-bars208/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/togo-breakfast-bars208/</guid><description>TO-GO BREAKFAST BARS yields 10 BARS ingredients 2 cup rolled oats* 2 cup rolled oatse* 2 cup rolled oats* 2 cup rolled oats* 2 cup rolled oatsd* 2 cup rolled oats* 2 cup rolled oats* 2 cup rolled oats* 2 cup rolled oats* 2 cup rolled oats* 2 cup rolled oats or almond butter
1/4 cup olive oil* 1/4 cup olive oil * 1/4 cup olive oil</description></item><item><title>TOFU RICOTTA</title><link>/recipes/tofu-ricotta209/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/tofu-ricotta209/</guid><description>TOFU RICOTTA yields 2 cup ingredients 1 block (14 ounces) extra-firm tofu 1 TBL olive oil 1/2 tsp grated lemon zest 1 TBL lemon juice 1/4 tsp salt 3 to 4 clove garlic 1/4 cup nutritional yeast Instructions 1 Pour the sunflower seeds into a food processor and run until that is in tiny-ass pieces.
2 Take the tofu out of its package and with your hands, squeeze out as much water as you can.</description></item><item><title>TOFU SCRAMBLE TACOS</title><link>/recipes/tofu-scramble-tacos210/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/tofu-scramble-tacos210/</guid><description>TOFU SCRAMBLE TACOS yields 8 TACOS ingredients 1 small crown broccoli 1 red bell pepper 1 yellow onion 1 carrot 4 clove garlic 1-2 jalapeños 1 TBL ground cumin 1 TBL chili powder 2 tsp dried oregano 2 tsp olive oil 1 block extra-firm tofu 2-3 tsp soy sauce 2 TBL lemon or lime juice 1/3 cup nutritional yeast 2 tsp hot sauce 8 tortillas Instructions 1 Chop up the broccoli into pieces no larger than a nickel, aiming for about 2 cup.</description></item><item><title>TORTILLA SOUP</title><link>/recipes/tortilla-soup211/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/tortilla-soup211/</guid><description>TORTILLA SOUP yields 4 AS A MAIN, 6 AS A SIDE ingredients 1 yellow or white onion 1 carrot 1 bell pepper 1 to 2 jalapeños 4 clove garlic 1 TBL olive oil 2 1/2 tsp each ground cumin, dried oregano, and chili powder 1/8 tsp salt 1 can (14.5 ounces) low-salt diced tomatoes 1/4 cup tomato paste 5 cup vegetable broth 1 TBL lime juice 6-8 corn tortillas, cut into 1-inch squares 1 1/2 cup cooked chickpeas Toppings: Chopped cilantro, minced jalapeños, avocado, shake from the bottom of your tortilla chip bag Instructions 1 Chop up the onion, carrot, and bell pepper into pieces about the size of a chickpea.</description></item><item><title>TWICE-BAKED POTATOES</title><link>/recipes/twicebaked-potatoes212/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/twicebaked-potatoes212/</guid><description>TWICE-BAKED POTATOES yields 6 PEOPLE AS A SIDE ingredients 3 large russet (baking) potatoes (about 3 LBs total), scrubbed but with the skin still on 1 TBL olive oil 1/2 large yellow onion 3 cup kale or spinach 3 clove garlic 1 1/2 cup cooked white or navy beans 1/3 cup unsweetened nondairy milk 2 TBL lemon juice 1/2 tsp smoked paprika 1/2 tsp salt 1/4 tsp black pepper Spray oil Instructions 0 chop onion</description></item><item><title>VEGETABLE PAD THAI WITH DRY-FRIED TOFU</title><link>/recipes/vegetable-pad-thai-with-dryfried-tofu213/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/vegetable-pad-thai-with-dryfried-tofu213/</guid><description>VEGETABLE PAD THAI WITH DRY-FRIED TOFU yields 4 ingredients 3 TBL water 3 TBL brown sugar 3 TBL tomato paste 3 TBL rice vinegar 14 ounces rice noodles 1 medium crown of broccoli 1/3 cup sliced shallots 4 clove garlic 1 cup sliced green onions 1/4 cup roughly chopped cilantro 2 tsp neutral-tasting oil Dry-Fried Tofu 2 cup thinly sliced cabbage 1 carrot, thinly sliced into matchsticks 1 cup bean sprouts peanuts Lime wedges Instructions 1 Mix together all the stuff for the sauce in a medium glass.</description></item><item><title>VEGETABLE POT PIES</title><link>/recipes/vegetable-pot-pies214/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/vegetable-pot-pies214/</guid><description>VEGETABLE POT PIES yields 4 INDIVIDUAL POT PIES OR ONE 9-INCH PIE ingredients 2 tsp olive oil 0.5 yellow onion
1 carrot carrot
1 cup frozen peas* 1 cup frozen peas* 1 cup frozen peas* 1 cup frozen peas* 1 cup frozen peast* 1 cup frozen peas* 1 cup frozen peas* 1 cup frozen peas* 1 cup frozen peas* 1 cup frozen peas* 1 cup frozen peasw* 1 cup frozen peas* 1 cup frozen peas</description></item><item><title>VEGETABLE-NOODLE SOUP WITH GINGER MISO BROTH</title><link>/recipes/vegetablenoodle-soup-with-ginger-miso-broth215/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/vegetablenoodle-soup-with-ginger-miso-broth215/</guid><description>VEGETABLE-NOODLE SOUP WITH GINGER MISO BROTH yields 2 BIG-ASS BOWLS OR 4 SIDES ingredients 4 inches fresh ginger 2 big clove garlic 1 carrot 6 cup vegetable broth or water 10 sprigs cilantro 8 ounces soba, udon, or rice noodles 1/4 tsp soy sauce or tamari 1 1/4 cup broccoli cut into bite-size pieces 1 1/2 tsp red miso paste 1 carrot, cut into thin matchsticks 1 cup snow peas cut into matchsticks 1/3 cup thinly sliced green onions Your favorite condiments Instructions 1 To make the broth, peel the ginger by scraping the skin off with a spoon.</description></item><item><title>VIETNAMESE RICE NOODLE SALAD</title><link>/recipes/vietnamese-rice-noodle-salad216/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/vietnamese-rice-noodle-salad216/</guid><description>VIETNAMESE RICE NOODLE SALAD yields 4 AS MAIN, 6 AS A SIDE ingredients 6 3/4 oz maifun or thin rice noodles 0.5 head lettuce 2 medium carrots 1 cucumber 1 cup mint leaves 1 cup basil leaves 1 cup cilantro 1 cup green onions Toasted Sesame Dressing, with 1 clove minced garlic added for an extra special something 1/2 cup salted, roasted peanuts, finely chopped Lime wedges, for serving Instructions 0 chop lettuce, cilantro, green onion; cut carrots, cucumber into matchsticks; slice mint and basil</description></item><item><title>WARM THE UP MINESTRONE</title><link>/recipes/warm-the-fuck-up-minestrone217/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/warm-the-fuck-up-minestrone217/</guid><description>WARM THE UP MINESTRONE yields 4 TO 6 ingredients 2 tsp olive oil
1 onion onion* 1 onion onionc* 1 onion onion
3 ribs celery ribs celery
1 large potato or turnip, cut into dice-size pieces* 1 large potato or turnip, cut into dice-size piecesr* 1 large potato or turnip, cut into dice-size pieces* 1 large potato or turnip, cut into dice-size pieces</description></item><item><title>WATERMELON HIBISCUS COOLERS</title><link>/recipes/watermelon-hibiscus-coolers218/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/watermelon-hibiscus-coolers218/</guid><description>WATERMELON HIBISCUS COOLERS yields 4 GLASSES ingredients 6 cup cubed watermelon* 6 cup cubed watermelone* 6 cup cubed watermelon* 6 cup cubed watermelon 2-3 tsp agave syrup or your favorite liquid sweetener instructions 1 Throw the watermelon on a rimmed baking sheet and put it in the freezer for at least 1 hour. 2 When the watermelon is nice and frozen, add it to a blender with the rest of the ingredients.</description></item><item><title>WATERMELON-STRAWBERRY TEQUILA PUNCH</title><link>/recipes/watermelonstrawberry-tequila-punch219/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/watermelonstrawberry-tequila-punch219/</guid><description>WATERMELON-STRAWBERRY TEQUILA PUNCH yields 18 cups ingredients 1 big seedless watermelon (about 16 LBs) big seedless watermelon (about 16 LBs)
4 cup strawberries (about 1 LB)* 4 cup strawberries (about 1 LB)r* 4 cup strawberries (about 1 LB)* 4 cup strawberries (about 1 LB)
1 1/2 cup tequila
optional *
1 TBL of your favorite liquid sweetener like agave syrup</description></item><item><title>WEDDING SOUP WITH WHITE BEAN BALLS AND KALE</title><link>/recipes/wedding-soup-with-white-bean-balls-and-kale220/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/wedding-soup-with-white-bean-balls-and-kale220/</guid><description>WEDDING SOUP WITH WHITE BEAN BALLS AND KALE yields 6 PEOPLE WHO CAME HUNGRY ingredients 1 large yellow onion 3 cup cooked white or cannellini beans 1/2 cup whole wheat bread crumbs 3 clove garlic 1/4 cup nutritional yeast or flour 2 TBL olive oil 1 TBL soy sauce or tamari 2 tsp seasoning blend 1 tsp each dried thyme, basil, and oregano 1/2 tsp grated lemon zest 1 tsp olive oil 2 carrots 2 ribs celery 3 clove garlic 1 cup small dried pasta 9 cup vegetable broth 1 TBL fresh lemon juice 4 cup kale or other dark, leafy greens 1/4 tsp each Salt pepper 1/4 cup fresh parsley or basil Instructions 0 chop carrots and celery</description></item><item><title>WHIPPED CREAM</title><link>/recipes/whipped-cream221/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/whipped-cream221/</guid><description>WHIPPED CREAM yields 5 cups ingredients 1 can (13.5 ounces) coconut milk, well chilled 2 TBL powdered sugar ½ tsp vanilla extract (Optional) instructions 1 You need some electric beaters or a stand mixer to do this. Stick the bowl and the beaters in the freezer for 15 minutes.
2 Take them out after 15 minutes and grab the coconut milk from the fridge without shaking it up. Open up the can and scoop out all the thick white cream on the surface and put it in the chilled bowl.</description></item><item><title>WHITE BEAN AND RED LENTIL BURGERS</title><link>/recipes/white-bean-and-red-lentil-burgers222/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/white-bean-and-red-lentil-burgers222/</guid><description>WHITE BEAN AND RED LENTIL BURGERS yields 8 LARGE BURGER PATTIES ingredients 1/3 cup red lentils 2/3 cup water 3 cup cooked white beans 0.5 red onion 3 clove garlic 1 jalapeño, minced 1/2 cup breadcrumbs 1 1/2 tsp smoked paprika 1 1/2 tsp seasoning blend 1 tsp ground cumin 1 TBL olive oil 1/2 tsp salt Grated zest of .5 lime Cooking spray Burger fixings, like buns, lettuce, tomato, onions, etc.</description></item><item><title>WHITE BEAN AND ROSEMARY HUMMUS</title><link>/recipes/white-bean-and-rosemary-hummus223/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/white-bean-and-rosemary-hummus223/</guid><description>WHITE BEAN AND ROSEMARY HUMMUS ingredients 1/4 cup vegetable broth or water 3 TBL balsamic vinegar 2 clove garlic 1 TBL minced fresh rosemary Instructions 1 Add everything to a food processor or blender and let that run until it’s nice and
creamy. You know, aim for hummus-like. You could do this by hand with a potato masher but
it will take a while even if you are ripped.</description></item><item><title>WHITE SANGRIA WITH MIDSUMMER PEACHES</title><link>/recipes/white-sangria-with-midsummer-peaches224/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/white-sangria-with-midsummer-peaches224/</guid><description>WHITE SANGRIA WITH MIDSUMMER PEACHES ingredients 1 bottle (750ml) white wine ½ cup brandy 4 white or yellow peaches, cut into slices 1 lemon, sliced into rounds 0.5 cucumber, sliced into rounds 1 bottle (750ml) sparkling white wine or 2 cup sparkling water instructions 1 In a big container or pitcher, stir together the wine, brandy, and fruit. (Don’t peel the fruit. Just throw it all in there.) Stick this in the fridge to chill for at least an hour or as long as overnight.</description></item><item><title>WHOLE WHEAT BANANA PANCAKES</title><link>/recipes/whole-wheat-banana-pancakes225/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/whole-wheat-banana-pancakes225/</guid><description>WHOLE WHEAT BANANA PANCAKES yields 12 PANCAKES ingredients 2 1/2 cup all-purpose flour 2 TBL brown or white sugar 2 tsp baking soda 1/2 tsp salt 2 cup nondairy milk (like almond) 1 small banana, mashed 1 TBL Grapeseed oil Instructions 1 In a big bowl, whisk together the flour, sugar, baking soda, and salt. Make a crater in the
middle and add the milk and mashed up banana.</description></item><item><title>WHOLE WHEAT BISCUITS</title><link>/recipes/whole-wheat-biscuits226/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/whole-wheat-biscuits226/</guid><description>WHOLE WHEAT BISCUITS yields 8 BISCUITS ingredients 1 cup almond or other nondairy milk 1/2 tsp apple cider vinegar 2 1/2 cup flour 1 TBL baking powder 2 tsp sugar 1/2 tsp salt 1/4 cup butter Instructions 1 Crank your oven to 425°F. Line a baking sheet with some parchment paper.
2 Mix together the milk and vinegar in a small glass and set it out of the way for a minute.</description></item><item><title>WILTED GREENS</title><link>/recipes/wilted-greens227/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/wilted-greens227/</guid><description>WILTED GREENS yields 2 AS A SIDE ingredients 1 bunch hearty, dark, leathery greens like kale or collards bunch hearty, dark, leathery greens like kale or collards
1/2 tsp olive or grapeseed oil* 1/2 tsp olive or grapeseed oil* 1/2 tsp olive or grapeseed oil* 1/2 tsp olive or grapeseed oil* 1/2 tsp olive or grapeseed oilice
1 tsp soy sauce or tamari
instructions 1 Remove the tough stems and slice the greens into strips about 1 inch wide and 2 inches long.</description></item><item><title>WORTH-THE-MESS SLOPPY JOES</title><link>/recipes/worththemess-sloppy-joes228/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/worththemess-sloppy-joes228/</guid><description>WORTH-THE-MESS SLOPPY JOES yields 6 REASONABLE SAMMIES, 4 IF YOU LIKE HUGE AND SLOPPY ingredients 2 tsp olive oil 0.5 yellow onion 1 red or green bell pepper 1 carrot 1 cup finely chopped button or cremini mushrooms 2 clove garlic 1 to 2 jalapeños, seeded and minced 2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 2 tsp smoked paprika 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp mustard powder 1 1/2 cup cooked kidney beans 1 1/2 cup cooked lentils (about ¾ cup dried) 1 1/2 cup tomato sauce 1 TBL apple cider vinegar or lemon juice 4 or 6 whole wheat hamburger buns, split and toasted Instructions 0 chop onion, bell pepper, and carrot</description></item><item><title>YELLOW SPLIT PEA AND GREEN ONION LETTUCE WRAPS</title><link>/recipes/yellow-split-pea-and-green-onion-lettuce-wraps229/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/yellow-split-pea-and-green-onion-lettuce-wraps229/</guid><description>YELLOW SPLIT PEA AND GREEN ONION LETTUCE WRAPS yields 12 TO 14 LETTUCE WRAPS ingredients 1 1/2 cup yellow split peas 3 cup water Salt 2 TBL soy sauce or tamari 2 TBL water 2 TBL rice vinegar 1-2 tsp of your favorite Asian-style hot sauce 1 tsp toasted sesame oil 1 tsp of your favorite liquid sweetener 2 tsp neutral-tasting oil 1/2 cup shallots or yellow onion 2 tsp minced fresh ginger 1 cup minced green onions 2/3 cup shredded carrot 3 TBL rice vinegar 1 1/2 tsp soy sauce or tamari 1 1/2 tsp toasted sesame oil 1 head of lettuce such as romaine or red leaf Instructions 1 Rinse the peas well and then throw them in a medium pot with the water and a pinch of salt</description></item><item><title>ZUCCHINI ROLLUPS</title><link>/recipes/zucchini-rollups230/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>tom.andrew.wilson@gmail.com (Thomas Wilson)</author><guid>/recipes/zucchini-rollups230/</guid><description>ZUCCHINI ROLLUPS yields 18 TO 24, DEPENDING ON THE SIZE OF YOUR ZUCCHINI ingredients 3 medium zucchini Creamy Pesto Dip 2 carrots, cut into 2-inch matchsticks 1 cucumber, cut into 2-inch matchsticks 1 red bell pepper, cut into 2-inch matchsticks 2 green onions, cut into thin strips, or a handful of chives Instructions 1 Chop the ends off of your zucchini so they are about the same length. Use a wide vegetable peeler or a sharp knife to cut wide planks of the zucchini lengthwise.</description></item></channel></rss>